[{"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "Tell me about a time when you took charge of a meeting. Was the outcome a positive one?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you have the confidence to lead a meeting successfully. Think about a time when you have driven a meeting - big or small. This example could be a phone meeting, a lunch and learn, or a large client presentation. \n\nBegin by telling the interviewer the reason for the meeting, who was involved, and what approach you took to prepare for the meeting. Finally, be sure to mention why you felt the meeting was a success! What did you do in that meeting to create an effective and positive outcome?", "\"My employer asked me to lead a lunch and learn meeting to train 15 employees on our new client management software. I was already a subject matter expert on the software so it wasn't difficult for me to plan the lesson. The challenge was making the content entertaining enough to keep the employees engaged. I created a strong PowerPoint presentation that included pop quiz questions throughout. The presentation was a success, and my employer asked me to lead a follow up meeting a few weeks later.\"", "\"Just last week my boss had a personal emergency and could not make it in time for our monthly staff meeting. Everyone was already gathered, and so he called to ask me to take control of the meeting. I feel that I did a great job relaying the information and my boss was thankful for the way that I was able to step in.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "At Company ABC we have many local competitors. In your opinion, what makes us stand out from the crowd?", "answers": ["It is crucial that you research Company ABC before your interview and be sure to learn about their business landscape. Who are their competitors? What are customers saying online? Check out some favorite review sites to get an idea of what the public is saying about Company ABC vs. their local competitors. Keep your answer positive and complimentary.", "\"After researching Company ABC online, I found that you stand out from the many ways that you give back to your community. On the Company ABC website, as well as third-party review sites, people are talking about the charitable contributions and generosity coming from Company ABC. These factors make your company a big stand-out to me because I am serious about working for an organization that is aware of their social impact.\"", "\"I believe that Company ABC has superior services and products. Your competitors seem to scratch the surface with some, but your offerings are so much more robust.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "When have you contributed to an effort to obtain a corporate goal?", "answers": ["Engaged employees are always the most productive. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of being an involved team member by assisting, in some way, to the end goal of the corporation.", "\"My most recent employer had an extreme interest in giving back to the community. So much so that we, as a group, logged our volunteer hours and it was treated as another KPI. We would review our community contributions on a quarterly basis. Our goal was always to hit a minimum 500 volunteer hours per quarter which meant that everyone would volunteer one day per month. It was a great initiative and one that I happily participated in.\"", "\"Everyday! The corporate goal is always my primary driver, in my current position. To be successful in my position I need to always be in tune with what my employer is trying to achieve, and be an active participant.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "How did you maintain a good relationship with your most recent boss?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you are capable of maintaining a harmonious relationship with those who are considered your leaders. \n\nIf your relationship with your boss wasn't fantastic, what efforts did you take to make it better? Here are some suggestions: \n\n- Try to understand what your boss values the most\n- Keep your cool, even when you want to lose it\n- Anticipate their needs and stay one step ahead\n- Take leadership opportunities to show your worth\n- Adapt to their preferences \n\nSome basic ground rules for a stable working relationship with your boss are open communication, proactive listening, and not taking things personally. Discuss the ways that you cultivated a healthy relationship with your boss.", "\"My current boss is a very particular individual. Over the years I have taken the time to understand her preferences, her stress triggers, and what she enjoys seeing in my work. I find that if I stay one step ahead and maintain a positive attitude, we can work productively together.\"", "\"I value having a strong working relationship with my boss.  I want to learn what they do and take on as much work to help our team as possible.  I scheduled regular update meetings with my boss and went the extra mile wherever I could.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "Many of the management and higher level roles with Company ABC require a Degree in Business or similar. Please walk me through your post-secondary education.", "answers": ["Your post-secondary background is on your resume; however, the interviewer is asking for you to go into further detail on your experience. This is a great time to brag a little bit about any scholarships, awards, or accolades you may have received during your post-secondary studies. Be sure to discuss how your education has prepared you for a position with Company ABC.", "\"I would be thrilled to be considered for a management level position with Company ABC. Although I do not have many years' experience in this type of position, I do have a Bachelor of Arts in Business Management from Walden University online. I graduated with a 3.6 GPA. I am very proud of this grade because I worked full time during my studies and still graduated top of my class.\"", "If you do not have a formal post-secondary education: \"I did not have the opportunity to attend University; however, everything that I have learned on the job has been incredibly valuable. I would be thrilled to join your management team down the road so if you feel there are gaps in my knowledge, I would be happy to consider attending any required classes or workshops.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "If you had $50,000 to build your own business, what would you do?", "answers": ["If money was no object, what kind of business would you start? The interviewer will be able to learn something new and unique about you through this question. Avoid answers that would include building a business that competes with the hiring company.", "\"If I had $50,000 to build my own business I would open up a community center in my neighborhood that offered inexpensive childcare, cooking classes, and other life skills programs. I am passionate about volunteering and see a strong need in those particular areas.\"", "\"I would choose to invest the $50,000 into an existing business in an industry that my spouse has an interest in. I love what I do for a career, but she has always wanted to be an entrepreneur.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "Tell me why you are the right fit for Company ABC,  and this position.", "answers": ["A successful hire needs to feel like the right fit by both parties. Express to the interviewer that you think this position is a stable fit for your experience and your career goals.", "\"I feel that I am the right fit for this company because, from what you have described, my personality, skills, and drive are what you are looking for. The challenges that come with this position are all challenges that I welcome. I am confident that this is the right fit for both of us.\"", "\"I am great at what I do, motivated, and I am an avid lover of your product. This mix creates a great match, in my opinion!  Happy employees are more productive and; trust me, I would be thrilled to work at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "Looking at your resume, it seems there are certain skills necessary for this position that do not stand out. How do you think you will be able to compensate for these missing skills?", "answers": ["Most job descriptions will have a long list of requirements. Hiring managers are aware that, to find a candidate that checks ALL of the boxes, can sometimes be impossible. If you are missing some of the \"nice to have\" or even the \"must have\" skills listed in the job description, do not fret! Be open about your shortcomings and discuss with the interviewer how you plan to compensate for those.", "\"I bring full dedication to learning, and mastering, any skills I do not currently have. I will compensate for any lacking skills through additional research. Also, I am happy to take any coursework that you feel would help.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "We value diversity at Company ABC. When have you worked amongst a diverse group of people?", "answers": ["Are you accustomed to working with a very large or diverse team of individuals? Assure the interviewer that you can handle an environment that offers diversity.", "\"I have worked with diverse groups of people most of my career, including my time in University. I am most comfortable, and happy, in this type of environment because it offers a great learning opportunity.\"", "\"In my current role, I work alongside cross-functional teams regularly.  Together, we manage our business and effectiveness. I enjoy the diversity component.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "What kind of people do you enjoy working with?", "answers": ["Culture fit is a critical factor when looking for a new position. Talk to the interviewer about the types of personalities that you best work with. Be sure to remain positive and avoid using this as an opportunity to speak poorly of previous colleagues.", "\"I best enjoy working with individuals who are driven, positive, energetic, and take accountability for their work. I do have the ability to work with a large variety of individuals; however, these are the ideal traits I would see in future colleagues.\"", "Some other great characteristics of co-workers: \n\n- Encouraging\n- Helpful\n- Engaged\n- Positive\n- Hard-working\n- Punctual \n- Reliable"]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "At Company ABC we provide services to a wide range of businesses. Which industry or business type do you have the most experience with?", "answers": ["In the commercial services industry, your experience with clients may be widespread. Talk to the interviewer about any particular industry to which you may have more exposure. If you have a specialty - now is the time to discuss your expertise. Whether you have experience in the same industry as Company ABC, or not, be sure to appear confident in your capabilities.", "\"I understand that the majority of business that is coming to Company ABC is related to XYZ. I have about four years of dedicated XYZ experience. The remainder of my work experience is with a wide range of clients and industries. I feel that these experiences have equipped me very well for a position such as this.\"", "\"I have the most experience in the manufacturing industry. Approximately 15 years, in fact. I believe this experience will benefit me in this role with Company ABC because I am well versed in best practices and manufacturing protocols.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "We have a wide range of services at Company ABC. Have you ever used any of our services?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you are well aware of the services offered at Company ABC. Have you used them previously? Discuss with the interviewer any exposure you have had to the company. Keep your response positive and lighthearted.", "\"I have not personally used your commercial services; however, I have friends who have used Company ABC for their business needs and their reviews were always positive!\"", "\"I have been a customer of Company ABC before, yes! The services I used were A, B, and C. My experience here was very comfortable, and everyone was professional. This experience is one of the reasons why I applied for this role. I want to work for a company that has high standards, and I know first hand that you do!\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "Due to the nature of Company ABC business and services we may ask that you complete a full background check. Are you willing to comply?", "answers": ["Many companies will ask for a background check before employing you. This due diligence could include a criminal record check, a credit check, a drivers' abstract, and education verification. The request will vary from company to company so you should always be prepared to comply with all requests. If there is a mark on your record, this is the best time to disclose that information. \n\nIf you have a clean record: \"I can fully understand why Company ABC would need to conduct background checks on all potential employees. I have a squeaky clean record and am happy to comply with any of your requests.\"", "\"I can fully understand why Company ABC would need to conduct background checks on all potential employees. I have a squeaky clean record and am happy to comply with any of your requests.\"", "If you have a mark on your record: \"I can fully understand why Company ABC would need to conduct background checks on all potential employees. I did have a charge against me approximately six years ago for a DUI. I have gained my drivers' license back since then, but I thought I should disclose that to you ahead of time.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire those who think outside the box. When was the last time you made a suggestion for workplace improvement? What was the outcome?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you are an engaged employee; offering suggestions and providing more profound thought when it comes to processing improvement in the workplace. Give an example of a time when you suggested an improvement in the workplace. It can be big or small! Did anything significant come out of your suggestion?", "\"Last year I made a recommendation for our office to incorporate a recycling program. We were going through a lot of single-use coffee pods. It bothered me how wasteful it all seemed. I presented a spreadsheet to my supervisor comparing the single-use pods vs. investing in a built-in coffee machine. The savings over two years were significant, and my boss has now presented my idea to our head office. It feels nice to be heard in the workplace, so I continue to keep my eyes out for opportunities for process improvements.\"", "\"I made some recommendations for change in our CRM system. The suggestions were surrounding how items received documentation and how outstanding tasks became highlighted. Our head office made the changes and a lot of people in our office commented on how much they liked the changes.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "Company ABC values philanthropy and community giving. How do you choose to give back to others?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you are socially responsible and a team player - even outside of the workplace. Your answer can be as simple as babysitting your grand-kids every Sunday, to a standing-volunteer gig, to charitable contributions.", "\"I work a lot but, when I do have free time, I spend that with my grand-kids. It helps to give my son a bit of a break as he is a full-time single dad. In addition to this, I volunteer at the local drop-in center every Christmas to help feed the homeless. Giving back is very important to me.\"", "\"Volunteering and charitable acts are important to me. I spend time volunteering at the local drop-in center every Sunday.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "At Company ABC, our primary work is to cater to other businesses. What do you foresee as the biggest challenge working in the commercial services industry?", "answers": ["Working in the commercial services industry can be challenging for a few reasons. You are working with businesses who have tight deadlines, varying business hours, and multiple departments with different needs. Briefly talk to the interviewer about the challenges you foresee in this role with Company ABC. Remain positive and complete your answer by commenting on your abilities to meet these challenges.", "\"This position sounds very exciting, and I understand that all roles come with their challenges. If I had to comment on potential challenges, I think the biggest one will be to learn this new industry and the language that comes with communicating with your clients. I am confident; however that I will meet your expectations as I am a quick and diligent learner.\"", "\"As in many industries, I believe that the biggest challenge in business is competing with all of the global e-commerce based organizations. They have less overhead and thus, can offer lower pricing. With that said, I do believe that Company ABC does a great job when it comes to building value for your customers.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "Customer service is our top priority at Company ABC. What is your customer service philosophy?", "answers": ["Because Company ABC puts so much effort into their customer service reputation, the interviewer needs to be confident that your customer service values align with theirs. Be sure to research the Company ABC website and take note of any keywords they use when it comes to their customers. Match your language with theirs.", "\"I noticed on your website that you put a lot of value into your customers by actively listening to their needs. You also survey them regularly while staying on top of industry trends so that you can provide them with innovative new services. To me, customer service goes beyond friendliness and efficiency. You need to understand your customer's business needs and have the ability to analyze their future needs so that you can respond appropriately to their business landscape changes.\"", "\"As overused as this phrase may be, 'Service with a smile' has always been my customer service philosophy. Very few people can resist a great smile and a friendly interaction! Friendliness warms customers up, makes them more inclined to work with you, and also diffuses a conflict quickly.\"", "\"I work hard at ensuring I build and maintain a trusting relationship with my customers. I lead with a servant's heart and passionately pursue excellence through service. I am an active listener. I elicit trust and share knowledge.\"", "Fantastic! This is a well-crafted response with detail and passion."]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "We value accountability at Company ABC. If a customer sent a formal complaint about an interaction with you, how would you handle it?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are a person of integrity who will take responsibility for any shortcomings in the workplace. Briefly explain to the interviewer that you will handle Company ABC customers with great care.", "\"I understand that Company ABC has put a lot of work into building these long-term client relationships. If one of your clients complained about my communication with them, I would take full responsibility for my actions and issue an apology. I would also be open to feedback to avoid future incidences. Rest assured, in my 15 years of employment, I have not had any clients complain to my employer about my work ethic or delivery of service.\"", "\"Constructive feedback is difficult to swallow at times, but it's helpful for me to remember that everyone receives constructive feedback from time to time. I will always do what is required of me to renew a client relationship.\"", "\"I first listen to the complaint, then express understanding. I ask a few questions to get as much information as possible before resolving the issue. I make sure to thank the customer for honesty and candid feedback. It is my responsibility to provide this candid feedback to my senior management to address the customer's concerns. We collaboratively discuss how to take care of the customer and provide them with the service we said we were going to provide.\"", "Wonderful! It sounds as though you have a robust process in place for dealing with customer-based issues."]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "Do you fully understand what we do at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Questions such as these are why it is essential that you research Company ABC before your interview. Dive deep into what they do, who their competitors are, who their clients are, and the impact their services have on their customers. Keep your answer as brief as possible and ask for clarification if you need it.", "\"From my understanding, the primary service offered by Company ABC is XYZ. You service large businesses such as A, B, and C. Without your services, most businesses would suffer because of 1, 2, 3. Would you like to provide me with more details on the core of your business?\"", "\"I feel that I have a good understanding of what you do at Company ABC from my research online, and on your website. With that said, I would love to hear more about it from your perspective.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "At Company ABC, we look to hire those who will be a long term fit. Where do you see yourself 5 years from now?", "answers": ["It's impossible to know where you will be in 5 years but you need to assure the interviewer that, given all possible circumstances, you could see yourself as a long-term fit for the position at Company ABC.", "\"Ideally, 5 years from now, I would love to see myself growing into a more prominent leadership role within your organization. My career interests align very nicely with your company's goals which helps me to see a great long-term fit here.\"", "\"5 years from now, I would like to supervise or manage a team of my own with Company ABC. I feel like I am progressing in my career at a rate that will make this a possibility.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "Sometimes the services and packages offered at Company ABC can be confusing to new clients. How do you explain complicated concepts to those who may not understand?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you are capable of explaining complex ideas without being condescending to your co-workers or talking over their heads. Give the interviewer an example of how you break down information to make it more easily digestible for the average person. \n\nThink of a presentation about a complex topic, as a proposal to solve a challenging problem. The solution may seem obvious to you, but everyone else in the room is scratching their heads trying to figure out what you're talking about. When you can define key terms and phrases to make them more relevant to your audience, you have skill! Not everyone can do this. \n\nPrepare an example that demonstrates your communication skills and your ability to convey complex information in easy to understand terms.", "\"I find that when there is a complicated concept to teach, visual aids are always the way to go. Did you know that 65% of people are visual learners and that presentations with visual components are 43% more persuasive? I took a course on creating effective info-graphics and will often implement those in my presentations.\"", "\"I use the K.I.S.S method...Keep it simple, silly!  If you cannot explain it simply, you do not understand it well enough.  I recently rolled out a complex compensation plan with many anomalies.  I took the approach to share a broad overview and provide detail for reference. I often try to make analogies or share complex information in the form of a story.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "Rate your communication skills from 1-10 with proper examples backing your given rating.", "answers": ["On a scale of 1-10, how skilled are you in communication? Why did you choose that particular rating for yourself?", "\"I rate my communication skills as a 9/10 as I will, on occasion, have times when I am not as clear as I would like to be. My supervisor and co-workers will attest to my clear and concise communication skills. Because I am an open leader, my team will let me know if I need to clarify anything.\"", "\"I will rate myself an 8.5 because I consider myself a strong communicator.  It is the foundation of all success in business.  I am always striving to be a better communicator, so I leave the rest of the scale as an aspirational measure.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "Considering your background is in an industry different from ours, what skills and characteristics do you have that qualify you for this position in this industry?", "answers": ["There are many ways that you can be a fit for a position, even though you do not come with direct industry experience. Think about the variety of skills that you have and how those can benefit another employer, despite the industry. These are your transferable skills, and they can include sales abilities, customer service experience, and software capabilities.", "\"Although my background is not in your precise industry, I have worked with many clients who have been in your industry. I bring excellent transferable skills that qualify me for this position. These skills include my advanced abilities in Excel, my outstanding cold-calling abilities as well as my proven background in team leadership.\"", "\"I bring many transferable skills to this position and industry.  My talents and skills revolve around helping people and making companies profitable. Customer service, problem-solving, and data analysis can cross any industry, and I am a pro at all three.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "Outside of work, what type of creative activities do you like to pursue?", "answers": ["A genuinely creative minded person will have outside activities aside from what's happening in the workplace. Tell the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you express your creativity.", "\"Outside of work I like to attend dance classes and I also attend the odd paint and sip wine nights at a local wine shop. I also enjoy reading as a way of nurturing my creative side.\"", "\"I think it's important to exercise creativity in a variety of ways. This reasoning is why I am involved in a variety of things such as team sports, reading, and art classes.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "How do you determine priorities when you have multiple projects due?", "answers": ["When you feel torn between multiple projects or tasks, how do you decide which one needs your attention the most? Assure the interviewer that you can be diligent when it comes to assessing your priorities.", "\"I will determine which project requires my attention by the number of hours we are behind and then the project size. I am comfortable delegating tasks when needed, but I am also aware that these times will require an additional commitment of hours from me. Never have I under delivered on a deadline.\"", "\"Assuming that the projects have different stakeholders, I interview each to determine the value of increased productivity, morale or revenue, decreased costs, and the overall impact.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "At Company ABC we value continued education and training. Tell me about your education.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know how your education has prepared you for this job. A few highlights you can focus on are some of the relevant topics you learned about while attending your courses. How will they help you in this new role? What were some of the most exciting things you learned? \n\nSome ideas for you:\n\n- If you have experience working on group projects, share how you improved your listening and communication skills when working on a challenging project. \n\n- If you learned a new type of software or how to work a kind of equipment you will need to know in this new job, talk about what you know and how you will apply this new knowledge.\n\nWhile attending post-secondary studies, you likely learned some core skills that would be transferable to any position. Think about what you learned in your highest levels of education and how that knowledge applies (or will apply) to your work. Some of these skills could include: \n\n- Time Management\n- Creative Thinking \n- Proposal Writing\n- Public Speaking\n- Presentation Building\n- Independent Learning\n- Academic Research\n- Self-Motivation", "\"I am a big believer in post-secondary education. It adds a lot of value to those newer to the workplace. My post-secondary education was in Communication and Journalism. The courses in this program helped me to develop stronger business relationships through professional correspondence. I also learned persuasive writing skills which have proven to be incredibly helpful when working on client proposals, and in negotiations.\"", "\"I have a B.A. in English and Spanish. I graduated with a 4.0 from ABC College, and I also worked full time while going to school, so I not only learned in my courses but also learned a lot of time management skills and how I work best under some degree of pressure. Academically, I refined my writing skills as well as gave a keynote presentation to several hundred attendees, thereby working on my public speaking and presentation skills.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "Tell me about a time when you used good judgement and logic to solve a problem.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to hear about a particular situation where you used good judgment to solve a work-related problem. Be sure to showcase your logic and reasoning abilities. Share a brief overview of the problem, discuss the pro/cons of each decision you could have made, and tell the interviewer why the solution you chose was the best.", "\"Just yesterday I had a customer who was upset because our sales associate would not refund a service that the customer had already used in full. She was outside of the 14 days return policy as well. I am the manager, so I stepped in to alleviate the situation. By showing the customer that I could meet her in the middle, she was able to calm down and reason with me. I did not refund her the full price; however, I offered her a $25 in service credit. I know this will cost my company mere dollars and, in the end, I had a happy customer again.\"", "\"I had a customer who was unhappy with his purchase (the service in question cost over $20k). He then was unhappy with the way in which the arbitration process was heading, and although my team all said just to let him be and have him work with our Director of Operations to resolve the issue, I knew that I could lose a customer over a one time issue. I mediated the call, allowed him to air his grievances, and assured him that we would work together to solve the issue.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "As a manager, who has been your greatest influence? A person that has defined what type of leader you wish to be.", "answers": ["Have you had a strong mentor in your management career? Talk to the interviewer about what type of influences have shaped your management style.", "\"The greatest influence in my career has been one of my Professors from University. Mr. Smith was my professor of Business Ethics, and I connected well with his teaching style. Even after graduating University, we kept in touch, and he has greatly influenced my coaching, teaching, and leadership style.\"", "\"The first CEO I reported to has been a tremendous influence on my career.  That person helped shape my work ethic and passion for business early on, which has helped me become a better business partner along the way in my career.  I wish to be someone who is fair, demanding and supportive.  Someone who cares about the customers and cares about our people.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "When a problem arises, what is your first reaction?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know if your reactions to problems reflect maturity and professionalism. How you react will significantly determine how you fit with the team at Company ABC. \n\nPerhaps your computer crashes, and you realize you may have just lost all of your hard work. Or maybe you are limited on time and have a deadline rapidly approaching. Demonstrate to the interviewer that you take a very methodical approach to problem-solving, rather than reacting in an impulsive way when a problem occurs.", "\"When a major problem arises, my first instinct is to take a step back and absorb what just happened. I then go into \"", "\"I have taught myself to become much calmer with my first reactions when problems arise. Now, I will step back and review my options for solving the problem rather than allow myself to become frustrated.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Commercial+Services", "question": "Strong time management is important at Company ABC. How do you manage your time, even on the busiest days?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about the types of tools you use to stay on task and meet deadlines. Discuss how you prioritize when everything demands your attention at once. Think about the ways you manage your projects and daily tasks and how those will help you to succeed in your role with Company ABC.", "\"I manage my time by exercising the idea of 'time-blocking'. This approach means that I won't incessantly check my email; instead, I will allow myself to return emails in 30-minute time blocks, four times per day. Setting calendar alerts and personal deadlines for myself has also helped a lot.\"", "\"Very carefully! I prioritize deadlines and work that need to be done.  Then work backward from there. When necessary, I utilize my resources and team to pitch in and contribute.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "With which applicant tracking systems are you most familiar? Explain to me how an ATS works.", "answers": ["Nearly every staffing company uses an applicant tracking system. An ATS collects resumes that are submitted to the agency online or by email. The ATS will collect, organize, and categorize the information on a resume in a way that helps you rank how well the candidate fits the position description. \n\nIf you need to research popular ATS' ahead of time, some of the most popular systems include: \n\n- Oracle Taleo\n- Bullhorn\n- Bamboo HR\n- Zoho Recruit\n- IBM Kenexa\n\nTalk to the interviewer about the systems you have used in the past. Be sure to showcase your knowledge on ATS systems.", "\"As a seasoned IT recruiter, I believe it's important that every candidate I work with has a full understanding of how an ATS works. I spend time coaching my candidates on how to optimize their applications, so they are successful against the applicant tracking parsing process. The systems I have used include Google Hire and BreezyHR. I am confident in my ability to quickly learn any new systems. Could you share with me the systems that you use at Company ABC?\"", "\"I have researched how an ATS works from both a recruiters standpoint as well as that of the candidate. I have heard of Kenexa and Zoho most frequently. Picking up on new technology is a strength of mine so, if you could share with me which ATS is used at Company ABC, I am happy to educate myself before my start date.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "Where do you go to source candidates, and in what order?", "answers": ["The interviewer is testing your recruitment expertise by looking for gaps in your sourcing process. One of the most critical activities in the IT staffing industry is to be the first to reach candidates. This achievement means working fast and searching smart! \n\nOften in the IT staffing industry, your clients will not be working exclusively with you. Talk about the steps that you take to ensure that other recruiters from Company ABC competitors don't reach your star candidate first!", "\"As soon as I take a new job order, I craft an eye-catching job posting and put it out to my LinkedIn network of over 5,000 contacts. Then, I sent out an SMS to every qualified candidate in my ATS who is at least a 75% match rate. My next step is to post on Zip Recruiter, which gives me multiple viable candidates within 24 hours. I have filled contract roles in as little as 18 hours with this approach.\"", "\"The most important, and the first place that I go to is to my existing database in my company's applicant tracking system. Second is LinkedIn, and third is my top four job boards, which include Indeed and CareerBuilder. I understand the importance of working fast and smart.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "Do you understand the pros and cons of temporary staffing versus permanent hire?", "answers": ["Company ABC offers a broad range of services to meet the ever-changing needs of their clients. Now, the interviewer wants to see that you understand the driving force behind some of the hiring approaches and decisions that your clients will make. Some factors a client will need to consider when weighing between temp and perm staffing include:  \n\n- If they are 100% sure of their future staffing needs. If there is an immediate need to fill a position, without a long-term guarantee, it may make more sense to hire a contractor versus a permanent employee.\n\n- Their ideal staffing levels. Will taking on more employees will be approved by their board or other stakeholders? In these instances, a contractor may feel less permanent.\n\n- Contractors may cost more per hour; however, they are often ineligible for perks such as paid vacation days, workers' compensation, and health insurance. This structure makes their fees very competitive, without the commitment. \n\n-  When a client chooses the temporary staffing route, they are not generally responsible for the contractors' payroll, or other time-consuming conversations such as truancy and performance issues. Less responsibility can save a client a great deal of time. \n\nTalk to the interviewer about your understanding of temporary staffing versus permanent hire. Show that you understand the factors that your clients will face when deciding their talent acquisition approach. Company ABC needs to be sure they are hiring a recruiter who will act as a staffing partner to their valuable clients.", "\"Many of my clients begin with a skilled contractor and then move them into a permanent position once they have proven their performance. We call it temp-to-hire, and my conversion rate with one particular client is 67%, which is remarkable. I believe this client feels safer in making hiring decisions this way. There is less risk of making a bad hire and dollars saved because they are not training the wrong people.\"", "\"From discussions with my clients, they prefer hiring contractors when they have an increase in projects and work, but there is an end in sight. I have one IT client who has a 1-year contract to create an app for a popular retailer.  When the contract is over, they may not have enough work to keep everyone busy. They need human resources to serve their clients' needs; however, they do not need a long term employee commitment. We staffed about 60% of their project, taking care of payroll, and more.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "What are your most important daily tasks as an IT recruiter?", "answers": ["The interviewer is checking to see if you have a full understanding of this IT staffing position. Think about the job posting or job description by Company ABC and the tasks and activities they mention most often. Show the interviewer that you have done your homework! If your current job is similar, talk about the tasks that you repeat most often. If you have never worked in recruitment, you will need to lean on your research and documents provided to you by Company ABC.", "\"As an IT recruiter, I can say that my most important tasks include calling and documentation! Calling current clients for new job orders, cold calling potential clients to form new relationships, and calling potential candidates to place them with my clients. From what I have read in the Company ABC job posting, you put a lot of emphasis on business development activities, and proper candidate follow-up.\"", "\"From my research and understanding, the most important tasks I would perform in this role with Company ABC include research, business development, and documentation. When I perform all three of these tasks at the level you expect, I should be exceeding my goals and targets.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "What would you do if one of your contractors quit their assignment without notice?", "answers": ["Temporary and contract staffing can be highly unpredictable. You may experience candidates who don't show up on their first day or quit their job without notice. Some contractors will decide partway through their assignment that the role isn't a fit. And, some will have life-changing moments and decide to leave their coding job to become a travel blogger. \n\nCompany ABC needs to know that you can put out these fires, and quickly backfill a position without taking too much time to recover. The key to this answer is showing that you are all about what's right for your client. Show that you react quickly, and with purpose.", "\"I understand that no matter how well you screen a candidate, these situations can still happen. If my placement quit under unexpected circumstances, I would ask a lot of questions about the job and overall fit, so that I could prevent the situation from happening again. I would work with great speed to find a replacement for my client. I would share the candidates' reasoning with the client so that we could make a plan to ensure the situation did not repeat itself.\"", "\"Exit interviews are critical in cases like this. I would ask the candidate what went wrong, what I could have done differently, and what my client could have changed. Next, I would apologize to my client and share the information from the exit interview. I would commit to finding a replacement within a suitable timeframe. Of course, I would document the situation and any conversations.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "Company ABC helps our clients grow and succeed by introducing them to top talent. How do you determine which candidates are the best match?", "answers": ["As an IT staffing professional, it's your job to make introductions! When a client has a need, how do you ensure that you are sending them the top candidates available on the market? Talk to the interviewer about your research skills, and your ability to properly vet candidates. Discuss the factors that you consider before sending a candidate over to your client.", "\"I highly respect my clients' time and the time of my candidates. For that reason, I only send my top 3-5 candidates for each open position. I look at an overall picture, which includes hard skills, soft skills, and culture match. I am clear with my candidate on expectations, the compensation package, and other significant factors in the company offering. A great match is one that goes both ways.\"", "\"The most important factors to look at when matching a candidate to a client are skill set but also personality match. I check to ensure that my clients' workplace culture is a match for my candidate. I want everyone to be happy, so I work extra hard to make sure that happens before ever making a candidate introduction.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "What do you know about Company ABC client base?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see that you have taken the time to research Company ABC and the clients they serve. You may not find a complete client list on the business website, but you should be able to uncover some reviews or client spotlights by searching online. Look for any information that shows you a few clients and industries that Company ABC serves.", "\"I am aware that Company ABC primarily serves the staffing needs of healthcare, finance, and government-based clients. I read stellar reviews from clients such as (A), (B), and (C). All of these companies are highly regarded in their space. and I look forward to learning more about your premium client list.\"", "\"You have excellent client reviews from the HR departments at (A), (B) and (C). In addition to this, I read many rave reviews on Glassdoor from candidates who you placed in government agencies, retail, and even biotechnology sectors. Your website highlights your work in the healthcare, life sciences, government, and communications industry. Is it accurate to say these are some key clients within these industries?\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "Company ABC specializes in staffing IT professionals within the technology, digital, creative, healthcare technology, engineering, life sciences, and government sectors. If you could recruit in any industry and specialty, what would you choose and why?", "answers": ["Any industry can call for the assistance of a recruiter; however, IT staffing can be especially challenging and specific. Some areas of IT recruitment include: \n\n- Accounting & Finance\n- Banking\n- Engineering (all types)\n- Legal\n- Data Security\n- Web and App Development\n- Government\n- Healthcare & Medical \n- Pharma & Biotech\n\nAs you can see, these are industries that often require a specific skill set and knowledge base. Talk to the interviewer about your specialty, if you have one. If you do not have one be prepared to discuss which industry you are most interested, and why.", "\"I have worked as a generalist recruiter and as a recruiter in the medical and healthcare industry. If I could choose any area for which to recruit, I would say that life sciences, would be of most interest.\"", "\"My university degree is in marketing, so I feel that I could be most impactful as a recruiter for sales, eCommerce, retail, digital, and creative industries. With that said, I am very open to learning new skills and industries.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "Talk to me about your sales training. Do you enjoy sales?", "answers": ["Much of IT staffing involves sales; whether it be finding new clients, asking for new job orders, or pitching a candidate to your client. In this role with Company ABC you might run a 360 desk. This term means that you handle everything from client acquisition, business development, sourcing candidates, and placing them, and all the documentation required in between. \n\nTalk to the interviewer about any sales training you have; whether it be formal coursework, post-secondary education, on-the-job training, or self-led learning. If you do not have any sales training, look into some online coursework that you can take, being sure to express interest in further training.", "\"I have completed coursework from 'Recruiting to Win' which included work on Pitching, Retainer Selling, and Networking Skills Training for Recruiters. This coursework, along with my years of experience in the industry, has helped me learn to prospect smarter, optimize my cold calls, and close clients more often. I am very confident in my sales skills but can always learn more.\"", "\"I am new to my career; however, as a recent university graduate, I see the importance of continual learning and skills building. I have a list of books that I am going to read over the next month, including 'The Psychology of Selling' by Brian Tracy and 'Way of the Wolf' by Jordan Belfort. These books will be beneficial; however, I am very open to your recommendations.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "How do you feel about working in a highly commissioned environment?", "answers": ["If Company ABC told you that you would be paid based on your performance alone, how would you feel? Many recruiters earn commission solely; however, not all of them do. It's essential that you fully understand the pay structure offered by Company ABC before moving too far into the interview process.\n\nWhether this position pays only commission is not the sole focus of this question. The interviewer would like to see that you are SO confident in your ability to be a top performer, that you would disregard a guaranteed salary. Show confidence in your skills but also be sure to only agree to a compensation structure that makes you comfortable!", "\"My job performance is always quality, and I have earned commission solely in the past, proving my value as a staffing expert. Now I am ready to jump into a role that offers a good salary plus commission, reflecting my years of training and expertise in the industry.\"", "\"A 100% commissioned environment would be new to me. After some sales training and a bit of lead time, I think I could certainly handle my pay structure as a reflection of my hard work. I am confident in my ability to be a high performer, either way.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "Walk me through your process after a candidate is rejected by a client.", "answers": ["Candidate rejection is part of your everyday work as an IT staffing professional. How you treat every candidate that you work with will speak volumes to the interviewer, and will be a significant factor in your fit with Company ABC. Talk to the interviewer about how you treat your candidates, ensuring that it is with utmost care and respect. \n\nThis respect means that you are forthright with them when they don't get the job and that you diligently follow up with them during the entire interview process. This question is a great time to show off your coaching skills, and your keen ability to give constructive feedback.", "\"I treat every candidate the same way that I expect in my job search. When my client tells me they are not the right fit, I will tell my candidate right away. Being upfront and prompt means that my client can take the time to process the rejection, correct their path, and move on to bigger and better. I encourage candidates by reinforcing their talent, despite the rejection. I have other clients that I can introduce them to, and I encourage them to keep in close contact with me throughout their job search. More often than not, I can introduce a talented candidate to two or more clients.\"", "\"It's important to respect candidates when they take the time to engage with you and your client. If my candidate is not selected, I pick up the phone and call them. If they are open to hearing feedback from my client, I will take the time to coach them and prep them for moving forward. Often this news is very disappointing o I must let them down easy, with respect and utmost honesty. I still work with these candidates closely because they are often a great fit for other clients.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "What steps do you take to ensure that you fully understand a clients' hiring objectives and requirements?", "answers": ["When you take a new job order from a client, your success in filling the role relies entirely on your ability to listen and ask the right questions of your client. The interviewer wants to see that you possess the insight and intuition to know how to get the correct information from your clients. Discuss what you do t ensure that you are on the same page of your clients, at all times.", "\"My ability to understand my clients' hiring objectives all comes down to asking the right questions. I always ask what went wrong with the last person in the role. I ask them to describe their ideal candidate, from skillset to mannerisms. I also visit my clients' office in person as often as possible so that I can get a full idea of the vibe; ensuring a workplace culture fit.\"", "\"To come from a place of full understanding, I begin by wholly reading the job posting, description, and the company website. It's important that I fully understand the core values and mission of my client so that I can match the best candidate. I ask a lot of questions that go beyond the standard, 'what is your candidate's ideal degree?' and look deeper into personality and culture.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "Walk me through your experience facilitating hiring decisions, including salary recommendations, benefits, other employment terms.", "answers": ["As an IT recruiter, you will play an integral role in ensuring that your clients and candidates are happy with the terms of their contract or job offer. This involvement requires you to be an expert in your clients' hiring landscape, which includes competitive salaries and compensation packages. Discuss your experience working as a partner to both parties, facilitating from the first interview to the job offer.", "\"I have run a 360 desk for the past five years. I take complete involvement in every placement I make, from job order to every touchpoint until an offer is signed, and into the first three months of employment. I keep up to date on the economic conditions of every region where I recruit. I am aware of the cost of living, salary averages, and dig deep into questions such as compensation packages and what my candidates need to accept a job offer. I am highly capable of facilitating these important conversations.\"", "\"As a research consultant, the bulk of my experience is in research and setting the stage for our staffing experts to coach clients on making competitive job offers. I read many publications on the art of compensation negotiations and what forms a great job offer. I look forward to learning more and increasing my involvement in these aspects of staffing.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "Do you have more experience with permanent placement or contract recruitment?  Which do you prefer?", "answers": ["Permanent placement and contract recruitment each come with their unique challenges, and the interviewer would like to know if you have expertise in either. Some recruiters are generalists, working in any industry and for perm or temp placements. Others stick to one lane. If you are new to the IT staffing industry, you will likely begin in temporary or contract recruitment. Before accepting any job offer from Company ABC, it's crucial that you fully understand where your focus will be.", "\"I have the most experience in contract recruitment within the IT space; mainly healthcare and government placements. Contract recruitment is fast-paced, and a bit more unpredictable than permanent placement, which I like. No day is the same. I have quick wins and can solve complex problems in a fast-paced setting.\"", "\"The staffing experience that I have is as a research consultant intern for a generalist firm that offered both permanent and contract-based opportunities. Although I have not formed a preference yet, I am aware that each area of staffing come with challenges. I look forward to learning everything that I can from Company ABC in any facet you require.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "Company ABC offers many growth opportunities into sales, operations, corporate and more. What are your long term career goals within IT staffing?", "answers": ["There are many areas to take your career in IT staffing, and the interviewer would like to know which of these avenues interest you the most. Some of your choices with Company ABC may include being a recruitment consultant, a branch manager, a recruitment specialist, a national or enterprise account manager, or a business development lead. Discuss where you would like to see your career go with Company ABC while being as specific as possible.", "\"My long term goal is to gain a role as a branch manager with Company ABC. What would make me a good fit for this is my ability to influence and motivate a team while keeping a keen eye on performance goals. I have an interest in helping my company optimize profitability by leading and supervising talented recruiters.\"", "\"Once my internship is complete, I would like to earn my way into a recruitment consultant role. I have some experience researching new lines of business, which is a great start for this role. I aim to gain more experience in understanding clients' needs, relationship building, and filling client orders.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "What economic factors impact the staffing industry the most?", "answers": ["Economic trends significantly impact the staffing industry. When a region experiences a significant industry boom, talent acquisition professionals need to look outside of their area and typical recruitment approaches to attract fresh talent. When the economy is weaker, often temporary or contract recruitment increases, where permanent searches decrease. Talk to the interviewer about the economic factors that you believe impact staffing the most.", "\"From my experience in the staffing industry, I have seen that situations such as tech and oil booms impact us the most. In an economic boom, staffing experts need to look outside the region for talented contractors. This demand also means higher pay and more commission for those working in staffing. Just last year our agency began to source IT workers outside of the country, helping many to obtain H1B visas, so they were eligible to work for our clients.\"", "\"I believe that the cost of living is a significant factor that impacts staffing. I have recruited for tech organizations in high-cost locations such as San Francisco and New York. One challenge is finding the fine balance between meeting the high salary requirements of the most talented candidates while helping my clients to keep their costs in check.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "Much of the work at Company ABC includes cold calling candidates and other prospects. Walk me through your cold calling experience.", "answers": ["Many IT staffing companies ask their recruiters to start with cold calling. If you are new to the industry, your training could require you to make 100 or more cold calls per week! So, for obvious reasons, the interviewer needs to be sure that you are not intimidated by the thought of making cold calls. \n\nDiscuss your experience with cold calling, and even warm calling to drum up business from existing prospects. If you have formal training in cold calling, be sure to mention that training. This training could include on-the-job or even self-led learning.", "\"The best book that I have ever read on the art of effective cold calling is 'Fanatical Prospecting' by Jeb Blount. This book taught me a lot about bad sales tactics versus a professional approach. In my current role, I received a great deal of training on filling my pipeline, building relationships, and exceeding my goals. Currently, I cold call up to 60 prospects per week with a 30% conversion rate, which is very good considering my goal is 50 cold calls at a 15% conversion rate.\"", "\"This position would be my first with a cold calling component; however, I have performed some door-to-door sales. On my summers off during university, I worked as a door-to-door canvasser for United Way. We had many targets and goals, which included knocking on 150 doors per day and raising a minimum of $1000 daily. It was a tough job, but I believed in the cause, which made the hard work worth it. I look forward to furthering training in cold calling and the opportunity to apply my previous sales experience.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "You land a new job order from a client. What do you do next?", "answers": ["As an IT staffing expert, part of your role includes carefully taking new job orders from your client. Taking a job order requires asking thoughtful questions so that you can gain a solid understanding of who will be the best fit for the job. Once you have a solid understanding of the type of candidates your client wants to see, check your ATS for candidates who are a match. You will want to craft a job posting and publish it on the platforms that your company leans on the most. Then, narrow down your candidate results and start making calls!", "\"Once I have a full understanding of my clients' needs, I go to my system and search for existing candidates. I will call from my top 15 list, asking if they are still looking for a job. If the role is a potential match, I will book the first interview. If the role is not a fit, I will ask them if there is anyone in their network who may be a fit. From there, I post on Zip Recruiter, our company website, Indeed, and LinkedIn. I also utilize LinkedIn recruiter to help me find matches. Generally speaking, I spend the first three days after receiving a job order on calling potential candidates and leveraging my network.\"", "\"After landing a new job order, I believe that proper documentation would be the first important step. After documenting, I would craft a compelling job ad based on the information given to me. Then, the path of least resistance would be to search my existing candidate base for a match. Is this the process followed at Company ABC?\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "Have you ever been unsuccessful in filling a clients' needs? If so, how did you react?", "answers": ["IT staffing and contract recruitment mean that you are often fulfilling urgent client needs. There are many variables in whether or not you are successful in being the top staffing expert that uncovers a rockstar candidate in a short amount of time. Often you are competing against other staffing agencies on the same job order.  \n\nThe interviewer wants to see that you can handle the pressure of this fast-paced environment at Company ABC. Discuss how you react when you fall short or run into a perceived failure. Express that you never give up, that you have grit, and the tenacity required to succeed at Company ABC.", "\"Recently, I had a client give me five days to fill two Python specialist roles. I filled one of the two; however, I do not consider 50% to be a success. Rather than feeling discouraged, I kept calling my network and sourcing online. I ended up introducing my client to the second and final hire the following week. This example goes to show that tenacity is everything in the staffing industry.\"", "\"I recently had a healthcare client who needed a role filled with a highly specific skill set. I knew I was facing a significant challenge; however, I underestimated the scope of the challenge. The role took me eight weeks in total and, in the end, another agency beat me to the punch. My approach involved all resources available to me, including diligent cold calling; however, in the end, it wasn't enough. I reached out to my client the following month, and they were happy with their choice; however, they did give me two new job orders, which I ended up filling. In the end, it wasn't a complete fail.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "What targets and goals are most important, in your current role? How is your performance measured?", "answers": ["Staffing is incredibly competitive, and your job as an IT recruiter is essentially a sales position. The interviewer wants to see that you are accustomed to the idea of meeting sales targets and other performance goals. \n\nAs an IT recruiter, in permanent or contract placement work, you may be measured on the number of placements you make per quarter, how quickly you fill a job order, your business development activity such as cold calling, and your interview-to-hire ratio. Talk to the hiring authority about your performance, and discuss how you stack up compared to others on your team.", "\"My current position involves both permanent and temporary placements. I look at my client acquisition strategies, which include cold calling numbers and conversion rate. I am judged on how many job orders I bring in, first interviews performed per job order, number of placements, and my interview-to-placement percentage. I have always landed in the top 3 performers for our agency. I attribute this to my warm and cold calling activities which are always over the minimum expectation.\"", "\"In IT contract staffing, the most important metrics in my role are the speed at which I fill a job order. I do not run a 360 desk, so right now, my expectations are based on how fast I react to the job orders that hit my desk. Right now, I am in the top place for telephone interviews performed, and I am among the fastest on my team to get candidates out to clients for first interviews. I am a strong performer, and I look forward to bringing this winning attitude to your agency.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "If you could change any aspect of the IT staffing industry, what would it be?", "answers": ["No job is all sunshine and rainbows, and the interviewer would like to know that you come with a realistic outlook on the industry and your job function when you join Company ABC. Think about any roadblocks you face on your path to success. Perhaps there are process or regulations that often prevent you from working as fast as you could. Avoid complaining about these factors. Instead, the interviewer wants to hear a more actionable approach.", "\"If I could change anything about the IT staffing industry, I would change the speed at which many of my clients respond. I believe that a candidate should never be left waiting for longer than 24 hours between responses. When seeking out IT candidates that are qualified and interested, it's important to act quickly before a competitor scoops them up. To ensure this speed happens more often, I prompt my clients regularly and begin each job order with the expectation of speed clearly expressed.\"", "\"I believe, from my own job search experience, that companies could further embrace the AI technology available to them. There is a lot of tech out there that streamlines the interview process, helping to keep the momentum and make the most of everyone's time.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "Company ABC goes beyond only matching resumes with open jobs. We help to grow and develop the careers of our candidates. How will you contribute to this mission?", "answers": ["Activities to grow and develop your candidates can include interview coaching, free skills testing, resume development, or even STEM education opportunities. The interviewer at Company ABC wants to see that you are interested in helping your valuable candidates to succeed in their job search. This interest in their success should go beyond whether they land in a job with your client or not.", "\"It's important to me that every candidate I approach feels empowered in their job search. This empowerment means that they understand the hiring landscape and that they understand their edge. I help my candidates craft their credibility statements, strengthen their LinkedIn profiles, and build a strong foundational resume. I also assist with interview coaching before they meet with my clients. Rest assured I would work hard to meet Company ABC goals of developing and empowering candidates.\"", "\"I will contribute to Company ABC mission by showing every candidate what they can do to boost their performance in an interview and gain more attention in their competitive space. I am great with LinkedIn profile optimization, which is one significant benefit my candidates receive. I appreciate that Company ABC is so mindful of how your teams can positively impact a candidate's job search.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "How would you define STEM? Why is it important?", "answers": ["STEM is a term you will often hear in the IT staffing industry. STEM is an acronym for science, technology, engineering, and mathematics. STEM education involves the interdisciplinary learning of these applications; an education background that many of your clients at Company ABC may seek. Discuss what you know about STEM education and why it's becoming increasingly vital in the IT space.", "\"STEM jobs are abundant, and the overall approach is expanding and growing. STEM education is important because many of my clients look for interdisciplinary learning and experience in science, technology, engineering, and math. I often look for STEM education on a candidate's resume, perhaps in the form of artificial intelligence or machine learning.\"", "STEM is short for science, technology, engineering, and mathematics. STEM education is highly sought after by clients in the IT space, meaning it's essential for candidates to begin expressing an interest in the STEM approach and furthering their STEM education. I wholeheartedly believe that  STEM is becoming a non-negotiable in the workforce to succeed in a global market and economy.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "How comfortable are you with using tools such as LinkedIn Recruiter to source new candidates and clients?", "answers": ["LinkedIn Recruiter is one of the most popular tools used in the staffing industry and Company ABC needs to know if you are familiar, or if you would require training. LinkedIn Recruiter makes it very easy to search, connect with, and reach out to qualified candidates all around the world. You can also use LinkedIn Recruiter as an extension of your CRM and ATS, keeping excellent documentation on clients and candidates alike. \n\nDiscuss your exposure to the program. If you have experience in LinkedIn Recruiter, talk about your years of experience and the tools that you utilize most often. If you are new to LinkedIn Recruiter, be sure to express your willingness to learn the system before your start date.", "\"In my current job, I use LinkedIn Recruiter every day. I use many functions of LinkedIn to search for and track the best candidates. I also use LinkedIn Sales Navigator to fill my pipeline and track my business development efforts. All of my activity is synched with our CRM and ATS, making this tool incredibly helpful.\"", "\"I have been on LinkedIn for the past three years; however, I have always maintained a free and basic account. I have heard that LinkedIn Recruiter is a must-have tool for anyone in the staffing industry. To be better prepared for this role, I will begin watching tutorials online.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "What does attrition mean, and what are the most significant factors that impact employee attrition rates?", "answers": ["Staff attrition is a term used to describe the natural loss of employees, such as through retirement, resignation, or elimination of a role. In recruitment, you may hear your client talk about employee attrition rates. What this means is that your client is reducing their number of staff due to natural reduction, including resignation, retirement, or relocation. Show Company ABC that you understand what attrition means, and that you know the basic terminology surrounding staffing and employment.", "\"Staff attrition rates refer to the reduction of staff due to unforeseen or natural circumstances such as retirement or personal illness. I have helped many clients navigate attrition by working with them on proactive workforce planning. When a company sees where their employee attrition rates are going, they can act ahead and plan, rather than being reactionary.\"", "\"Attrition refers to the reduction of something so, in staffing, I believe this would be referring to a company's human resources. Because attrition is usually a natural occurrence, I think staff attrition would refer to resignations and retirement. Every company must work hard to plan for a strong future workforce, and I look forward to learning how I can best help Company ABC clients to do so.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "Rate your resume writing skills from 1-10. Are you able to help a candidate position themselves flawlessly to your clients?", "answers": ["As a staffing professional, you will find that optics are everything. Your candidate can be a perfect match, but if their resume does not reflect this experience, their application will be overlooked by your client. Prepping candidates to put their best foot forward is very important in this industry. This prep will include helping them to re-write their resume, or re-writing it yourself; highlighting the ways that they match your clients' needs. Talk to the interviewer about your resume writing skills, ranking yourself from 1-10.", "\"I am a member of the CPRW and certified in resume writing as well as career coaching. For this reason, I would rank my resume writing skills as 9 out of 10. There is always room to grow. Trends are constantly changing; however, I am very confident in my ability to best showcase a candidates' skill set. When I submit a candidate, my client always interviews them.\"", "\"I was a recruiter assistant during my internship. Much of what I did was optimize candidate's resumes for applicant tracking systems. I enjoy helping people to stand out from the crowd. I would rank my resume writing skills as a 7.5 out of 10. I know how to write a compelling resume; however, my experience is limited to the past three months.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "What questions do you have for me?", "answers": ["When you have questions prepared for the interviewer, it shows that you have a keen interest in Company ABC and the inner workings of their business. Since you are interviewing for an IT staffing role, it's extra vital that you have insightful questions! This engagement will show the interviewer that you can ask candidates the right questions when you are on the other side of the interview table. Make them insightful and have 2-3 prepared.\n\nHere are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- Is this a replacement search or a newly created role? \n- What do you love about working at Company ABC?\n- What is Company ABC primary goal for this position in the first three months? \n- Can I clarify anything for you from our meeting today?\n- What do you see as the most significant change in IT staffing this year? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"Thank you for offering time for questions. Could you share with me your timeline for the next round of interviews? Also, since this is a replacement role, I would like to know the biggest struggle the previous recruiter encountered in this role. That information will help me prepare in areas where I may need additional training.\"", "\"After meeting me today, is there any particular reason why I would not be the best fit for this IT recruitment role? Also, I would like to know your favorite aspect of working for Company ABC!\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "Would you be honest with a candidate who did not get the job due to their appearance?", "answers": ["There are many reasons why a client could reject your candidate, including a messy appearance. As a recruiter, it's essential to recognize that optics can be just as important as someone's skill set. This statement is especially true if they are interviewing for a sales position or other customer-facing role. \n\nOf course, it's not fun to tell someone that they need to clean up their appearance; however, it can be your duty as a recruiter. Show Company ABC that you have the discernment and empathy do approach this type of situation with kindness and honesty.", "\"Every candidate I send on an interview receives a document that addresses where to go, the name of the interviewers, what the dress code is, and the overall 'appearance' expectations. For the most part, my candidates have been presentable. However, I have had two clients in the past complain that my candidates had body odor, likely a reaction to interview stress. It's uncomfortable to have a conversation like this but honesty is important to me, and both times the candidate was appreciative that I brought the issue to their attention. In both instances, my clients did a second interview and were satisfied with how I handled the situation.\"", "\"It's essential to be straightforward with job seekers, but with that must come kindness and empathy. If I had a candidate who was a perfect match for my client, but their appearance was lacking, I would let them know that their overall presentation would not fly with my client. I would ask permission to give constructive criticism, and then help them every step of the way.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "Exceptional IT staffing requires an intimate knowledge of the industry. How do you remain up to date on changes and trends within IT?", "answers": ["When you are having conversations with a candidate who works in IT, you must know your stuff! You should be able to understand the industry terms and much of the jargon they use when you interview them, and when you read their resume. Otherwise, how can you correctly determine a match? Tell the interviewer which resources you lean on to stay up to date on IT related topics and news.", "\"I subscribe to CIO Magazine which I use as my primary source for information. The reason I lean on this resource so much is that it's for senior-level IT professionals, which most of my clients and candidates are. The publication also does an excellent job blending business and technology. It also offers a great deal of advice appropriate for career development at the senior level, which I can then pass along to my candidates.\"", "\"The Verge and Recode are my go-to resources at the moment. The articles are beneficial, but I especially appreciate the emphasis on tech journalism. If you have any other recommendations for me, I would love to learn more.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Staffing", "question": "What are your earnings expectations as an IT recruiter?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know, bottom line, what you need to accept a job offer from Company ABC. There is a lot of back-and-forth in salary negotiations with clients and candidates in this industry. For this reason, you can expect the hiring authorities at Company ABC to be to the point when it comes to compensation based questions. Be straightforward, using your current salary if it's relevant.", "\"My earnings expectations are $100K+ per year. I have earned between $96-106K annually for the past five years. I am a high performer. My current pay structure includes a monthly guarantee of $4K and the remainder in commission.\"", "\"Being a recent graduate, and new to the IT staffing industry, my earnings expectations reflect my eagerness to join your company with room to grow. I am willing to begin on a small base salary of $24K plus commission.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "Have you ever broken a confidentiality agreement?", "answers": ["Companies will have confidentiality agreements for a variety of reasons. These could be to protect their trade secrets or to ensure that you do not bring clients over on the occasion that you leave their company. Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on confidentiality agreements.", "\"I never have, to my knowledge, broken a confidentiality agreement. Despite my reasons for leaving a position, I would never choose to hurt a previous employer in any way.\"", "\"Confidentiality agreements are necessary and important to protect an organization.  I understand the need for confidentiality and take those factors very seriously. I have never broken the trust of my employer.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "How would you rate your performance in this interview so far?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking for your honest thoughts on how you feel about your interview performance. Be truthful and transparent, even if you think that the interview could have gone better.\n\nIf you feel that your performance in the interview is going well: \"I believe that this interview has been informative, and I am happy with my performance. Is there anything that I can clarify for you from this conversation?\"", "\"I believe that this interview has been informative, and I am happy with my performance. Is there anything that I can clarify for you from this conversation?\"", "If you feel that your performance in the interview is not going well: \"I am not sure if I have been able to portray myself 100% accurately in this interview; although, I am trying my best. If there is anything more  I can clarify for you, I would be happy to do so.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "What type of manager brings out the best in you?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see that you are self-aware and understand the type of manager or employer that brings out the best in you. Some individuals prefer a close working relationship with a lot of accountability while others prefer space and autonomy. If you are unsure of the management style of the interviewing company, try to leave your answer as open as possible. You can certainly ask the interviewer to describe their management style.", "\"I have worked with a wide range of personalities and management styles with great success. If I could express a preference, I feel that I am best in an independent and autonomous environment. Can you describe the management style here?\"", "\"I work best with managers who are highly communicative and approachable. I don't enjoy working in a hierarchy based environment as I find it does not offer room for new ideas and creative thinking. How would you describe your management style?\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "We have a very specific personality type that fits well with the strong corporate culture at Company ABC. Describe your personality in 3 words.", "answers": ["This question is a high-stress question if you are not prepared to discuss your personality, and characteristics. Rather than freezing up during your interview or saying something you regret, take a few minutes to jot down some ideas before your meeting. \n\nReview Company ABC website and see if you can source any recurring keywords in their job postings or 'About Us' section. Any recurring themes or keywords will give you a great idea of the type of personality and characteristics that Company ABC is looking for.", "\"If I could describe my personality in 3 words I would say that I am communicative, helpful, and enthusiastic. I know that Company ABC is looking for individuals who work well as part of a team, and someone who brings a great amount of energy. That is me! I would be a great fit for the culture you have created here.\"", "Here are some other words you can use to describe your personality: \n\n- Adaptable\n- Considerate\n- Diligent\n- Inventive\n- Persistent\n- Resourceful\n- Sensible"]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "When have you had to change a major component of your project due to new information being presented?", "answers": ["Being able to swivel the focus of your project is a necessary skill for your success in most careers. Talk to the interviewer about a time when a significant change occurred on a project. How did you handle the implementation of the new information?", "\"I had a large project last month that was nearly complete when the client called to say that the dimensions provided were incorrect. Because of this, our team had to re-do the entire proposal. It took us an additional four days of work but, in the end, the client was delighted with our work, and it resulted in new opportunities with them.\"", "\"I had worked with a VP in the company, the CEO, and a member of the board to craft a strategic national roll-out plan that included which companies and pitches I would be responsible for, and what they would handle. Two months later, after working on the strategy each week as a collaborative team, I was informed that we were putting a pause on the project until further notice.  The executives thought the company wasn't ready for such big clients yet, so instead, I had to scale the national roll-out back to be a local market strategy. After the initial sting and frustration of pulling out of the project, I was able to use that same framework to plan local market roll-outs in several major cities effectively. It proved to be a good learning experience, overall.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "If you could start your career over again, what direction would you take?", "answers": ["A hiring manager will be able to tell a lot about your personality by learning about your other career interests. If you could do anything over, what would you do, and why?", "\"I certainly do not regret the direction I have taken my career; however, if I had to start over in a new direction completely I would likely pursue my Degree in Education and become a teacher. Both of my parents were teachers, and they seemed to have a very fulfilling career. I enjoy coaching and leading others so, any tasks in my current career that related to these skills, are very welcome.\"", "\"I am delighted with the direction my career has taken. If I could change anything I would perhaps have furthered my education to include a unique focus; however, I have no regrets!\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "How would you describe your relationship with your customers or clients?", "answers": ["Do you value your client and customer relationships? How do you nurture them to ensure that they are happy and continue to come back? Talk to the interviewer about your strategy for building strong customer and client relationships.", "\"My customer and client relationships are open and honest. I believe that the more upfront and transparent you are with your clients, the more likely they are to return. I most definitely value my clients and am sure to nurture those relationships as much as possible.\"", "\"I have strong relationships with my clients and customers. I treat them with respect and am sure to utilize their feedback in ways that make myself, and the organization, better.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "Tell me about a time when you took on a new course to study in order to improve your own work performance.", "answers": ["Once you are in your career, it certainly doesn't mean that you need to stop learning. There are many job-related courses available. Talk to the interviewer about the last time you took advantage of these available courses.", "\"Our company offered the Sandler Sales program to anyone in the company who was interested. I took this workshop in 2014 and enjoyed it. My sales increased by 23% that year.\"", "\"I took a one-day seminar in Microsoft Excel.  I already knew the basics, but my boss like using macros and pivot tables, and I was spending a lot of time reading the support section to figure out how to use them.  The course was very informative.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "How do you evaluate success among your team members?", "answers": ["When you are leading a team, it is imperative to be aware of the level of success that each team member is experiencing. One underperforming team player can drag down the entire group. Talk to the interviewer about how you can stay aware of each team members' success.", "\"I have a very in-depth and successful system for evaluating success among my team members. I check in twice per week with each member of my team. On Monday's - to set our goals together. Then, on Friday's, to discuss any successes and challenges. I have them self-evaluate, and then we create a plan for success for the upcoming week. I evaluate their success based on their follow through and willingness to work hard to reach their goals.\"", "\"I typically have KPI's (key performance indicators) in place to measure the success of each of the members of the team. I also manage our overall success in working together. For example, are we hitting on key initiatives within the department, developing each other for succession planning and having fun along the way!\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "How would you prefer to be compensated?", "answers": ["Are you looking for a compensation structure based primarily on salary, commission, or a blend of both? Discuss with the hiring manager your compensation preferences.", "\"I am currently compensated primarily on a base pay of $60,000 with the opportunity to earn a quarterly bonus based on the company's profits. I would like to be compensated similarly in my next position.\"", "\"I am currently making a salary with a bonus incentive on a quarterly and annual basis.  I would like to continue down that path but am open to exploring other compensation components such as commission, or working on a draw system.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "This position with Company ABC requires strong research skills. What is the first resource you turn to when you need to research a person, business, or topic?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you can source information when and where you need it. In this industry, and with Company ABC, you must be in-the-know and on top of your client's needs at all times. Talk about where you first go for information when you need it the most.", "\"When researching, my go-to source is usually LinkedIn. This website offers me a plethora of information whenever I need it. I can research clients, their businesses, their backgrounds, and their competitors in one place. I find LinkedIn to be a very reliable, up-to-date, and convenient source.\"", "\"For me, when researching, using a reliable source is key. For that reason. my resources will always be a legitimate news website or books published by known authors.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire those who can read between the lines in order to uncover our client's potential needs. Give me an example of how you have successfully done this.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you understand the nuances that come with this job. When you work for Company ABC you must be able to think independently and out of the box at all times. This type of thinking will increase client happiness, sales results, and will help to expand your portfolio. Give one real-life example of how you helped a client by reading further into their potential needs.", "\"One example I can give is when one of my larger clients went through a corporate restructuring last year. I was able to help them fill in some gaps in their service needs as I saw potential shifts in their business. Because I have assisted many clients with restructuring projects in the past, I was able to foresee some of the roadblocks they may face and offered my assistance there. The client was very pleased with my proactive approach, and I was able to upsell additional services.\"", "\"With each new client that I take on, I conduct a detailed questionnaire with my primary contact. I ask tough questions regarding the pain points in their business. From these answers, I can predict some of their needs faster than they can.  I believe this is because it's harder to see your needs when you are directly in the middle of the scenario. Sometimes, it's easier for outsiders to uncover your business' most significant needs.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "In this role with Company ABC you will be required to make regular presentations to our clients. How comfortable are you with public speaking, and creating PowerPoint presentations?", "answers": ["If you know ahead of time that presentations are going to be a part of this position, feel free to bring a previously crafted PowerPoint presentation with you, on a tablet or iPad. Otherwise, be prepared with some examples that include the number of people you have presented to, what the range of topics has been, and what the outcome was. \n\nYou can also make your answer very clear by rating yourself from 1-10 on your PowerPoint and public speaking skills. If you have any formal training in public speaking, be sure to talk about that as well.", "\"I am very comfortable with public speaking and would rate myself as an advanced user in PowerPoint. I have attended multiple Toastmaster classes to perfect my public speaking skills. In my current position, I will present to groups from 3 people to 90, ranging from 'lunch and learns' with my internal team to the entire department for my client. I receive consistently positive feedback on my presentations because I like to keep them engaging through the use of analogies and sharp visuals.\"", "\"I am an intermediate user in PowerPoint and have no problem improving my skills to an advanced level. When it comes to public speaking,  my experience is limited; however, enough to know that I do not suffer from stage fright. I would very much enjoy further exposure to public speaking and the delivery of presentations.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "We have many strong competitors. What makes Company ABC stand out, and how could we improve?", "answers": ["It is essential that you research Company ABC before your interview and be sure to learn about their business landscape. Who are their competitors? What are customers saying online? Check out some favorite review sites to get an idea of what the public is saying about Company ABC vs. their local competitors. Keep your answer positive and complimentary.", "\"After researching Company ABC online, I found that you stand out from the many ways that you give back to your community. On the Company ABC website, as well as third-party review sites, people are talking about the charitable contributions and generosity coming from Company ABC. This factor makes your company a big stand-out to me because I am serious about working for an organization that is aware of their social impact.\"", "\"Without having worked in Company ABC, it is tough to give suggestions on improvement accurately. I quite like what I have seen so far and feel that your company stands out through your quality standards and search for constant improvement.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "What do you know about our clients at Company ABC and the types of services we offer?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you have put some effort into getting to know their business and the types of clients that Company ABC services. You can find this information online by combing through the company website or doing a Google search. Discuss with the interviewer what you discovered during that research. It is okay to ask the interviewer more about the services and clientele at Company ABC as well.", "\"From what I understand, you provide services primarily to clients within 'ABC Industry'. Your range of services is quite broad which was a big pull for me when applying to Company ABC. Could you tell me a little bit more about your primary client base?\"", "\"I have conducted a great amount of research on Company ABC before coming here today. I believe that your product range is vast and it would attract a very diverse set of clientele. Is this correct? The one service that stood out to me was (name a service) because it offers exceptional value to established business owners and new entrepreneurs, alike.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "We have a healthy yet competitive culture at Company ABC. How do you track your personal successes and metrics? How often do you look at your KPI's?", "answers": ["When working in the professional services industry, your results matter! No matter your job function, you should always be prepared to discuss your career-related successes. Talk to the interviewer about your recent achievements and show Company ABC why they should hire you!", "\"My current company offers a very robust tracking system where I can view my current metrics on a daily basis. I check these metrics every day because they measure me against my monthly average as well as the company average. It's important in this line of work to keep up to date on results. By keeping on top of my KPI's, I can improve my performance and results whenever necessary.\"", "\"In my opinion, the only possible option is to review my KPI's at the beginning of each day and the end of each day. I track my successes and progress through our company CRM and make a plan every morning related to what I need and want to accomplish. At the end of each day, I assess my progress so that I am prepared mentally for the following days' activities.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "At Company ABC we do everything to ensure that our clients are satisfied. What is your client service philosophy?", "answers": ["Because Company ABC puts so much effort into their customer service reputation, the interviewer needs to be confident that your client service values align with theirs. Be sure to research the Company ABC website and take note of any keywords they use when it comes to their clientele. Match your language with theirs.", "\"I noticed on your website that you put a lot of value into your clients by actively listening to their needs. You also survey them regularly while staying on top of industry trends so that you can provide them with innovative new services. To me, client service goes beyond friendliness and efficiency. You need to understand your clients' business needs and have the ability to analyze their future needs so that you can respond appropriately to their business landscape changes.\"", "\"My client service philosophy is simple and perhaps a bit traditional. To service someone truly is to be at their service, working with, and for, them to reach their goal together. For this reason, I will always go the extra mile to meet my client's needs. I want them to feel fully supported in their endeavors.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "Are you currently interviewing with any of our competitors? Why do you want to work for Company ABC over any of our competitors?", "answers": ["Every interviewer wants to know that you are specifically interested in their company. One way you can show your keen interest is by discussing howCompany ABC stands out to you, ahead of their competitors. If you asked whether you are interviewing with their competitors or not, you should answer in a direct but diplomatic way.", "\"I am actively interviewing; however, I am using strong discretion when it comes to the next step in my career. I do understand that some of your competitors are hiring and the positions are competitive. My deciding factor is on the corporate culture and overall reputation of the company. From what I can see, Company ABC stands out from the rest when it comes to employee engagement and client satisfaction.\"", "\"I have just started my search and have applied to a limited amount of companies. Rather than sending out multiple applications, I have chosen to be very targeted in my search. I want to work for Company ABC because, while being a fast-moving and innovative organization, you still maintain old fashioned values. I appreciated that about your organization and would be very proud to be on your team.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "This position requires a competitive yet collaborative individual. How do you plan to make an impact in your first 90 days with Company ABC while setting a strong groundwork of trust with your new team members?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to hear more about your plan of action should you be accepted for the position with Company ABC. Think about the skills gap that you could fill or any internal struggle that Company ABC is trying to resolve by hiring someone like you. \n\nDiscuss the ways you know you will make a fast impact but also address how you will ensure acceptance by your new team members.", "\"If hired for this role with Company ABC I would want to get to know my team by listening to their suggestions and recommendations for success. I have very strong follow up and up-selling skills that would result in a fast impact on the portfolio that you would be handing off to me. I am a naturally collaborative person, so I am confident that I will create quick results while maintaining strong relationships.\"", "\"I plan to make an impact in the first 90 days by being incredibly diligent throughout my training, taking work home to study on the weekends, and getting to know the verbiage used with your clients. I plan to be more than confident in my abilities, so that I can hit the ground running, without any hesitations.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "Tell me about a project you completed recently that was ahead of schedule.", "answers": ["Is it essential for you to meet and exceed work-related deadlines? Assure the interviewer that you can remain focused on a project and accomplish your goals ahead of schedule.", "\"In my current position I am expected to cold call 100 customers per week. Most of our associates will break this down into 20 per day, five days per week. What has attributed greatly to my success in this role is that I call 50 customers each day for the first two days and then have time to make additional calls throughout the week. This effort generally equals a 25% surplus of cold calls to my portfolio. I am always ahead of target by going over and above that cold calling schedule.\"", "\"In my current position, I was given the task of migrating our payroll system to a new provider. Happily, I completed the project two weeks ahead of schedule allowing us to start the new service sooner.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "What is the most competitive work situation you have experienced? How did you handle it? What was the result?", "answers": ["Think back to the times when you were racing others to achieve the best sales, working towards a promotion, eagerly trying to win a new contract or other situations that pushed you to rise above your peers.  \n\nBe sure to tell the interviewer that you rose to the challenge and were excited to see what you could achieve!  Tell the interviewer about how you kept yourself calm while pushing yourself to be the best.  It is a definite plus if you have cheered on your competitors and helped them along the way. Finally, be sure to mention your successful outcome.", "\"My last position was a sales position, and highly commissioned. We had a great work environment where we helped each other and built each other up. The result was a positive work environment, and I enjoyed coming to work each day.\"", "\"In my previous position, I worked with some very competitive individuals who were bordering the point of aggression. I can be as competitive as the next person; however, this was next level. I made the best of the situation by keeping my head in the game, remaining focused, and tuning out the unpleasantness of their competitive grind. In the end, I exceeded my targets at 105% to goal. I was happy with my results and the fact that I kept my integrity in place, at the same time.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "How do you handle communicating bad news to a fellow worker or subordinate?", "answers": ["One of the toughest parts of communication can be delivering bad news to people that you work with and for whom you care. Whether it is providing a less than positive work review, or terminating someone - it doesn't come easy. Assure the interviewer that you can handle this type of task in a clear, concise, and professional manner.", "\"I certainly do not enjoy communicating bad news to a co-worker, but I do have experience in doing so. When this type of task is required of me, I make sure to practice empathy. Truth is always key, so I will be honest and clear when communicating the news. For instance, if I am to terminate someone's employment, I will not sugar coat the reasons why. It's best they know so that they can learn from the experience.\"", "\"I have found that communicating with respect and the intent to support the associate is the best approach. It is important to communicate what behaviors are off track and what resources are available to the associate to get back on track.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "How do you explain complicated concepts to those who may not understand?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you are capable of explaining complex ideas without being condescending to your co-workers or talking over their heads. Give the interviewer an example of how you break down information to make it more easily digestible for the average person. \n\nThink of a presentation about a complex topic, as a proposal to solve a challenging problem. The solution may seem obvious to you, but everyone else in the room is scratching heads trying to figure out what you're saying. When you can define key terms and phrases to make them more relevant to your audience, you have skills! Not everyone can do this. \n\nPrepare an example that demonstrates your communication skills and your ability to convey complex information in easy to understand terms.", "\"I find that when there is a complicated concept to teach, visual aids are always the way to go. Did you know that 65% of people are visual learners and that presentations with visual components are 43% more persuasive? I took a course on creating effective info-graphics and will often implement those in my presentations.\"", "\"Keep it simple, silly!  If you cannot explain a concept straightforwardly, then you do not understand it well enough.  I recently rolled out a complex compensation plan with many anomalies.  I took the approach to share a broad overview and provide detail for reference. I often try to make analogies or share complex information in the form of a story.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "Outside of work, what type of creative activities do you like to pursue?", "answers": ["A genuinely creative minded person will have outside activities aside from what's happening in the workplace. Tell the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you express your creativity.", "\"Outside of work I like to attend dance classes and I also attend the odd paint and sip wine nights at a local wine shop. I also enjoy reading as a way of nurturing my creative side.\"", "\"Outside of work I love to explore my creative side.  I practice photography and take sculpting classes on a regular basis.  As an avid reader, I also explore writing.  Cooking is also art for me, and I try to incorporate creativity into the fun meals I prepare for family and friends.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "Tell me about your most significant work experience that relates to this position.", "answers": ["This question is an excellent example as to why it is crucial for you to review the job description, in detail, before your interview. Have you ever held a similar position to this one? Can you draw any similarities between this role and another job that you have had?", "\"In my most recent position I had many related responsibilities such as client relationships, customer service, and cold calling. The job descriptions are very similar; however, your role is a slight step up in responsibilities which would provide the growth that I am looking for.\"", "\"I am performing a role very similar to this one at my current employer. However, this role would be a step up for me.  After years of working in this field, I am ready for the challenge of leading a team.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "Do you prefer to work in a team based position or individually?", "answers": ["In which situation are you the happiest and most productive? Talk to the interviewer about your preference when it comes to teamwork or working individually. Be sure to avoid pigeonholing yourself into one particular scenario (IE: I only like to work by myself).", "\"I have found, in the past, that I work best in an individually driven environment; however, I can certainly be productive in a team-based setting as well.\"", "\"I am happy to work either with a team or independently. I truly do not have a preference. Does this position lean to one more than the other, or is there a balanced mix of the two situations?\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "When do you feel your leadership skills are most effective?", "answers": ["When you have a great relationship with the individuals you are leading, your leadership skills will be the most effective. \n\nShow the interviewer that you recognize a great relationship starts with clear communication, trust, and honesty. Tell the interviewer that you spend time genuinely getting to know your team. \n\nFor instance, perhaps you like to understand what activities they have going on both inside and outside of work, their kids' names, or if they have any pets. Building a relationship with your team will ensure that you can frequently and genuinely ask them how they are doing.  The more comfortable they are, the better chance they will come to you for help in the workplace when they need it.", "\"My leadership skills are the most effective when my relationship with the employee isn't just a surface connection. I want to have true knowledge of their life and a good understanding of their career goals. When my employees feel confident that I can help them to achieve their goals, they are more likely to be an engaged part of the team.\"", "\"My skills are most effective when we face a tight deadline and have to push through. I pride myself on being and an excellent motivator.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "How do you balance life and work?", "answers": ["It is essential to keep a healthy work/life balance to prevent burnout. Talk to the interviewer about how you can maintain that appropriate balance for yourself.", "\"I find that with the right company, it's pretty simple to balance life and work. When I enjoy what I do, it doesn't feel like a chore. I am always sure that when at home, my family gets my attention first. I take time on the weekends to do things for myself and ensure that I regenerate before the work week begins.\"", "\"I balance life and work by ensuring that my downtime is spent doing the things that I love. I enjoy hiking, playing squash, and going to the theater. These things energize me and help me to maintain a healthy balance.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "What sources do you look to when you need to solve a complicated problem?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you can think outside the box, or even ask for help when you are stuck on a complicated problem.\n\nMaybe you look to a mentor or boss for advice. Perhaps you have handbooks, manuals and systems you turn to for help. Offer some relevant examples based on your industry. If you work in the medical field, you may turn to textbooks, online research, colleagues or even patient's history to find the right solution. If you work in customer service, you may ask the customer what they need to find the best way to solve the problem. \n\nShow the interviewer that you are knowledgeable and equipped to handle these types of scenarios.", "\"When faced with a complicated problem, I will look to the resources that my current company has provided me. The answer is almost always in there. If it's more of a moral dilemma vs. a knowledge-based dilemma, I will ask my supervisor for his thoughts and opinion since I value him as a mentor and expert in our industry.\"", "\"If there's a complicated problem, I'll write out what I think the possible solutions would be, and make a note of what my gut tells me to do. Then, I will weigh those potential solutions against one another and list the complications that may arise as a result of each choice. Also, I am always open to input or suggestions from those with more experience than I and look to my mentors, their experience, and the training resources, as well as potentially talk the problem out with coworkers or my boss.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "What would you do if a client asked you about a product or service and you were unsure of the answer?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know if you are an independent thinker. Explain that you would take the time to try and figure out the answer, but you are not afraid to ask questions if you need to.", "\"If I had a client ask me about something that I didn't know enough about, I would find the answer for them before giving a false answer. I am okay with admitting when I don't know something, and I love to learn new things. Of course, I would find the answer quickly by asking the appropriate person or finding it within the company's internal resources.\"", "\"I am accustomed to having to think on my feet and come up with a creative answer based on the information I have at hand. With that said, I'm not going to tell a client something that is untrue or could potentially create a long-term issue. I'm not afraid of putting myself in a position where I don't know everything or am not the expert. I am happy to get out of my comfort zone to grow, learn, and help a customer. I will not hesitate to involve the appropriate parties, do my research, and work collaboratively to solve the situation.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "How do you motivate others on your team?", "answers": ["You don't have to be a manager or a team leader to motivate others. Offering a listening ear or providing words of encouragement can make a world of difference to your coworkers. Sometimes, just being a positive influence and showing up consistently can also make a difference. \n\nIf you have worked in a leadership role, think of ways you helped set clear goals or helped individuals cultivate a new skill. Reflect on your experience and share some ways that you have helped encourage others to keep up the good work!", "\"I motivate my fellow team members by coming to work with an exceptional attitude every day. I won't allow anyone's bad mood to let me down. That influence alone has helped many of my coworkers get through their day on a more positive note.\"", "\"I motivate others by complimenting their work, asking them their opinion, and making them feel like a valued part of the team.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "What is your long-range career objective?", "answers": ["Onboarding new employees is a time consuming and costly endeavor, so the interviewer wants to make sure that this role will be a long-term fit for you. Be open with the interviewer about your dreams within this company, on a long-term basis.  Share what promotions you hope to eventually receive and discuss what you wish to learn from being a part of their organization. The key to answering this question is to express to the interviewer that you plan to be employed by the company for many years to come.", "\"While visiting your company website I noticed that you have some leadership opportunities available in a variety of locations. I would love to work my way into a management or leadership role with your organization and would be willing to relocate to do so. I really like what your organization stands for, and I hope to see a current fit, and future growth, here.\"", "\"That is a great question! I see myself leading a small team of like-minded and passionate individuals who enjoy the work we are accomplishing together.  I also see myself working closely with a charity to give back to the community.\""]}, {"topic": "Professional+Services", "question": "How do you manage your time?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about the types of tools you use to stay on task and meet deadlines. Discuss how you prioritize when everything demands your attention at once. Think about the ways you manage your projects and daily tasks.", "\"I manage my time by exercising the idea of 'time-blocking.' This process means that I won't incessantly check my email; instead, I will allow myself to return emails in 30-minute time blocks, four times per day. Setting calendar alerts and personal deadlines for myself has also helped a lot.\"", "\"Very carefully! I prioritize deadlines and work that needs completion then work backward from there. When necessary, I utilize my resources and team to pitch in and contribute.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "How does artificial intelligence impact talent sourcing?", "answers": ["Artificial intelligence (AI) made it's splash on the staffing scene many years ago, with the introduction of ATS or applicant tracking systems. Today, AI is becoming smarter and more robust, making it easier to source and screen the best candidates. Talk to the interviewer about the ways you have seen AI change talent sourcing strategy.", "\"The most dramatic change I have seen in the talent sourcing and staffing industry has been the marriage of AI and affordable SaaS. Job postings and other tasks, automated by solutions such as Zip Recruiter, do a lot of initial sourcing and screening for HR professionals. This ease of use and its affordability means companies who once relied on a staffing agency are utilizing this technology for themselves. To overcome this, staffing agencies must offer the best and fastest service, proving more than ever before that their fees are worth paying.\"", "\"Applicant Tracking Systems are getting smarter every year, and once I learned how to utilize an ATS to my benefit, my recruitment process sped up exponentially. Now, I can deliver talented candidates to my clients' inbox in just a day or two, fully screened, and ready for their first interview. I also believe that tools such as LinkedIn Recruiter, which rely heavily on AI for search results, have greatly benefitted the staffing industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "What type of clients come to Company ABC for our staffing services?", "answers": ["Company ABC helps a plethora of clients from small businesses to enterprise-level companies. Check out the company website to look for client reviews and any other indicator of whom their clients might be. The most important factor with this question is to show that you have done your research on Company ABC before attending your interview.", "\"There are many rave reviews on your website from companies big and small. I see that you have reviews from (A) and (B) which are very impressive. I have recruited for clients in similar industries and even direct competitors in the past. This experience will ensure that I catch on very quickly to your clients' varying needs.\"", "\"I believe that clients of Company ABC consist of any sized business who need help finding rare skill sets or who need to volume hire for seasonal operations. Although I did not see any specific clients listed on your website, I suspect your biggest clients are within logistics and warehousing, administration, and sales. Is this accurate to say?\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "How do you build trust and rapport with your clients?", "answers": ["For Company ABC, client relationships are everything. Excellent client service and strong relationships are what separate successful agencies from those who struggle. As a staffing professional, you know that anything is possible; from finding unicorn candidates to closing temp contracts in a matter of hours. \n\nShow the interviewer that you know what it takes to build strong client relationships. Your relationship-building activities can include asking your clients questions about themselves, setting clear expectations and guidelines at the start of every search, and learning their industry language. Exceptional follow-up is another way to build trust with your clients quickly.", "\"As the lead permanent search recruiter, I am always the first person that a potential new client sees. To build a strong relationship from the start, I make sure that I look professional and capable. First impressions are indeed everything. I ask insightful questions that stand apart from other recruiters with whom they have met. Most importantly, I empower my clients to understand stellar recruitment practices. I become their partner in staffing versus just another recruiter looking for a fee.\"", "\"The fastest way to create a trusting relationship with my clients is to deliver candidates to them much faster than they anticipated. I like to present my first candidate within 24 hours of receiving the job order. This speed means that I win over other recruiters while showing my client that I care about their needs. I earn many other job orders from this approach, as well as countless referrals.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "Tell me about the targets and goals in your current position. Do you have trouble meeting them?", "answers": ["Every staffing professional knows that there are targets and goals to meet within their agency. In temporary recruitment, these targets often relate to the speed at which you fill open job orders or the volume of work that you get from your clients. \n\nIn permanent staffing, goals can include the fees you have collected each quarter, or how many job orders you brought in through cold calling efforts. \n\nTalk to the interviewer about the goals and targets in your current position. If you are not sure of the goals present in this role with Company ABC, it is certainly okay to ask.", "\"In my current position I have a heavy focus on new client acquisition and business development activities which includes performing at least 60 cold calls per week. I always meet my performance targets, which also include job order volume, first interviews conducted, and placement fees collected. This month already, I am 154% to my placement fee goals.\"", "\"I am measured on how quickly I fill my temporary job orders and the number of new job orders that my existing clients send me every month. My average is 20 job orders per month, with an expectation of just 15. I am a high performer, and I look forward to bringing this winning attitude to Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "How often do you check in with your candidates after placed in a permanent role with your client?", "answers": ["Many staffing agencies will have a schedule of events when it comes to checking in with candidates after placing them with a client. These check-ins are vital as they are meant to ensure that your candidate is happy with their new placement and that they are meeting performance expectations. \n\nMost staffing agencies offer a free replacement to their client, should a candidate not work out for the best within 90 days of their employment start. For this reason, it's best practice to have regular check-ins for the first 90 days, and into the persons' first year. Show the interviewer that you understand the importance of this practice and that you are a diligent staffing professional.", "\"I have a schedule for checking in on every single one of my permanent placements. I check in on their first day and at the end of their first week. After their first week, I have a weekly check-in for the first 30 days. From then, every other week until they reach their 90 day probation period. From 90 days to year one, I schedule a monthly email. All of my candidates appreciate my diligence in ensuring they are happy with their placement. This action allows me to react to any potential situations before they become a major issue.\"", "\"I believe it's best to check in on the morning of their first day, and twice more during the candidate's first week. For the first 90 days, I will email or call once per week. Then, I check in monthly. These conversations are usually short. I ask questions related to expectations versus reality, their overall comfort level, and happiness with their new work environment.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "How does a staffing agency charge a job seeker for their services?", "answers": ["This one may be a trick question! Legitimate staffing agencies never charge job seekers for placement services. That's right; every placement fee paid to a staffing agency is from the hiring company. \n\nIn many countries, such as Canada, it is illegal for a recruitment or staffing agency to charge candidates for job placements. These regulations do not include fees for resume writing or career coaching, for instance. The bottom line is, a job seeker never pays money to be considered for an open position with a staffing agency or their clients.", "\"All placement fees are paid for by the client, rather than the candidate. In my current agency, we charge the client between 18-25% of the candidates' first years' salary. This fee structure means that if the candidates agreed upon salary is $100K, then our fee would be $18-25K; never paid for by the candidate. I understand that different regions have various fee structures. However, I believe that a client should always pay the agency placement fee. No financial burden should fall on the job seeker.\"", "\"Placement fees are paid to a staffing agency when they successfully place a job seeker in a new role with their client. Fee percentages vary; however, an agency should always invoice the hiring company. A candidate may pay for assistance such as resume writing or career coaching; however, they do not pay the employment placement fee.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "If a temporary employee let you down regularly, what would you do?", "answers": ["Temporary employment can be a challenge to navigate, especially in industries such as warehousing and logistics. These challenges come because: \n\n- Candidate volume and placements are high\n- Wages are average but competitive\n- Hours can be sporadic\n- Client communication is often lacking due to shift work \n\nIf a candidate let you down regularly by being late, no-showing to their assignment, or failing assessments such as forklift driving skills; what would you do? Show the interviewer that you have patience, that you are empathetic but firm at the same time.", "\"At the end of the day, it's my client who needs to be happy with the temporary employees that I provide them. If I had a temp who was continually failing to meet expectations, I would have to let them go. Anytime we drop the ball; it can negatively impact on my clients' bottom line, which is never a welcome situation. On any offense, such as being late or not showing up, I will call the temp employee and find out what happened. I ask for open lines of communication, and if we continually miss the mark on expectations, then I need to move on and put my energy elsewhere.\"", "\"I believe in setting expectations from the start. I let temporary employees know what will occur should they fail to come to work or show up for their assignment on time. For the most part, I have excellent working relationships with our temp employees. When I need to let a temp employee go, I still educate the person on work performance expectations, and I encourage them to try their best in the future.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "What is a staffing agency?", "answers": ["This question may seem as fundamental as they get, but the interviewer needs to know that you understand how staffing works. Staffing is a misunderstood industry. It will be part of your role to add clarification for clients and candidates who may not fully comprehend what it is that you do. Briefly describe to the hiring authority what a staffing agency is, including who they help, and their primary purpose.", "\"I come across many candidates who do not understand what a staffing agency is. I explain to them that a staffing agency works on behalf of other companies to help them find the best talent for their open jobs. I explain that most of my clients do not have the time to filter through thousands of job applications per year, or hire in a timely fashion, so they ask for outside help.\"", "\"A staffing agency is like an extension of a company's human resources department. When a company is too busy to keep up with their recruitment needs, a staffing agency will come in to help them source candidates, pre-screen for job skills, and conduct first interviews.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "What is the difference between temporary, temporary-to-permanent, and permanent placement?", "answers": ["Temp, temp-to-perm, and perm are recruitment and staffing terms that you will hear every day while working for Company ABC. \n\nWorking temp means that a contractor is on a temporary contract with the staffing agency, to work for their client, for a specific amount of time. Temp employees are paid directly from the staffing agency, and the agency then bills the client. \n\nTemp-to-perm is a contract that begins temporarily with an opportunity for the contractor to be hired on full time once their work performance is proven. \n\nPerm or permanent placement is when candidates undergo a traditional screening and hiring process with the agency and their client. In the end, the hiring company makes a permanent job offer to the candidate. \n\nTake a few moments to share your knowledge with the interviewer.", "\"I get this question from candidates a lot, and it's best to keep the answer straightforward. Temp work is contract work that can last anywhere from a couple of days to a year or more, depending on the company's hiring needs. The contractor knows the assignment can end at any time, without notice. Temporary-to-permanent occurs when that contractor is asked to stay on as a dedicated employee after the original contract period is up. Permanent placements are traditional offer-to-hire gigs where an agency's client will hire the candidate as a dedicated payrolled employee.\"", "The most significant difference between temp, temp-to-perm, and perm are the expectations set from the beginning. Temp employees are paid by the staffing agency to fulfill a specific client need for an agreed-upon length of time. Temp-to-perm contractors may have the opportunity to be hired on full time once the contract is complete, and their performance is proven. Perm refers to traditional employment where a company offers to hire the job seeker immediately.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "Is honesty the best policy?", "answers": ["As a recruiter or staffing professional, you will come across some grey areas including pay structures, fee structures, rules governing contract employees, and non-compete or non-disclosure agreements. It's vital to the reputation of Company ABC that you abide by rules and regulations carefully, always working within the ethical lines of recruitment. \n\nYour response can also include how honest you are with candidates when it comes to your clients' needs. You could also mention your transparency when closing off with candidates not chosen for the job.", "\"Yes, I believe that honesty is always the best policy. I deliver honest news with as much empathy as possible. I will never hold back from telling the truth when it means so much to another person to hear it. If a client does not want to move forward with a candidate, I will let them know right away and give them open feedback whenever possible. When it comes to paperwork and the legal ins and outs of supplying employment opportunities, I always abide within legal limits and regulations.\"", "\"I understand that there are known 'grey' areas in recruitment, primarily from agencies that do not present themselves in the best light. One of the reasons I applied to Company ABC is because of your long-standing sterling reputation in the industry. This excellent reputation comes from being honest and forthright with candidates and clients alike.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "How do you determine job order priority?", "answers": ["Prioritizing job orders when you have multiple open requests at one time can be a tricky task. You may want to consider factors like: \n\n- The clients' preferred start date\n- The difficulty level of a search\n- Whether the search is exclusive\n- The candidate market in the role's location/region \n\nShow the interviewer that you will not have a problem sorting your job orders at Company ABC ensuring every client is taken care of promptly.", "\"I lean on my CRM a lot when it comes to prioritizing tasks. I rank jobs in order of importance in an A, B, C fashion, along with setting up goals, dates, and milestones. My system prompts me when a deadline is approaching. Some clients needs are more urgent than others; say a new search versus an unexpected replacement. Overall, I never allow a client to go more than 48 hours without some movement from me.\"", "\"Non-exclusive roles often receive priority. Also, temp gigs tend to require a fast turnaround, sometimes less than 24 hours between order to fill. Next, I prioritize by how responsive my client is, and their preferred start date.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "What will be your primary focus in your first 30 days with Company ABC?", "answers": ["There are many tasks and accomplishments that you can focus on when working in the staffing industry. This question is meant to uncover if you have a plan to make an impact on Company ABC shortly after being hired. Much of the staffing industry involves sales-based tasks, so it's a great idea to go into your interview with a strategic plan for your first 30 days, and onward. Talk to the interviewer about your goals once you join Company ABC.", "\"From our conversation, I understand that you need a staffing expert with experience in business development within various engineering sectors. Once I have my footing at Company ABC, I plan to approach the hiring authorities in my network who work within various arms of engineering. In the first 30 days, I aim to bring in 15 new job orders. In the next 60 to 90 days, I will boost that goal to 25 each month. I am confident in my ability to grow into this role quickly while exceeding your business development expectations.\"", "\"Once hired at Company ABC, I plan to dive into my training, bringing my studies home, and taking time in evenings and weekends to master the content given to me. It's important to me that I learn the staffing industry quickly so that I can begin making an impact when it comes to research, prospecting, and business development activities.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "Have you ever worked with a staffing agency, from a job seekers' perspective?", "answers": ["If you have ever experienced staffing from the perspective of a job seeker, you can understand the recruitment process from a variety of perspectives. This experience allows you to be empathetic with job seekers who may be nervous working with a recruiter and their clients. \n\nTalk to the interviewer about your experience working with a staffing agency. If you do not have this experience, that is okay too! What is most important is that you show Company ABC you have the empathy and patience needed to work with candidates who do not understand the goals of staffing.", "\"A few years ago I was headhunted into the role that I have now. This situation was my very first time being on the other side of the table and, honestly, it was a little bit intimidating! Even though I knew the staffing industry in and out, I was still unsure of next steps and felt a lot of pressure to impress multiple parties. I wanted to interview well with the company and not let down the recruiter who was working so hard to place me. This experience gave me a new perspective, and now I treat candidates with even more care and concern. I am clear on next steps, expectations, and give them every tool possible to help them succeed.\"", "\"Although I have not worked with a staffing agency, as a job seeker, I completely understand how the situation could be confusing and intimidating. To combat those feelings, I work closely with my candidates and am always open for questions along the way. I help my candidates with articles, guides, and information to ensure their success through the entire recruitment process.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "When scanning a resume for the first time, what do you look for?", "answers": ["Stats show that a recruiter will give a resume between seven and eleven seconds of their attention before moving on to another resume. Experts in the staffing industry know how to scan and screen a resume for the most critical information, so they can easily shortlist or disqualify. \n\nWorking at Company ABC, chances are most of the resumes you will receive will first be screened by your applicant tracking system. Still, many more resumes will come through to your email. Show the interviewer that you know what to look for in a resume when you initially screen.", "\"When I am scanning a resume for the first time, I will first look to see if they meet my clients' educational requirements. Then, I look at their dates of employment to see if they are a job hopper. Next, I look at their job title and industries they have worked for, ensuring their career progression makes sense. I also want to know if they have worked for my client in the past. If they pass these initial checks, I will call them for a prescreen telephone interview.\"", "\"Job hopping is the first thing that I look for in a resume. If the candidate has held more than five jobs in three years, I disqualify them. It's nearly impossible to ask a client for a hefty fee when there are no guarantees this candidate would stick by them. Next, I look for a match with industry, education, and ensure that job titles and movement make sense. Did someone go from sales rep to CEO in 6 months? I would need to know more since that would be an unusual career progression.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "Do you understand how Company ABC makes a profit?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see that you understand the fee structure at Company ABC or at least staffing agencies in general. Depending on your region, this response could vary as there are different rules and regulations surrounding staffing and recruitment around the world. \n\nFor the most part, a staffing agency makes a profit in three ways: \n\n1. Permanent placement fees\n2. Temp fees\n3. Retainer based searches \n\nPermanent placement fees are usually a set percentage based on the ideal candidate's salary. Let's say that a staffing agency is asked to headhunt a chemical engineer. The staffing agency finds the perfect candidate, and that chemical engineer comes with an asking salary of $100K per year. The hiring company would pay (in addition to the $100K salary) a fee of 18-25% that number, as a permanent placement fee. So, a one-time $18-25K fee. \n\nTemp fees are a surcharge in addition to a temporary employee or contractors' hourly wage. Assuming the same chemical engineer is working on a 12-month contract for an oil and gas company. The OG company does not want to add this engineer to their permanent payroll or pay the engineer's employment insurance and other government required fees. The staffing agency will take on the role of 'employer' and charge the additional costs plus a commission to the OG company. Let's say the chemical engineer is asking for $40/hour. The staffing agency will charge the OG company $55/hour, giving $40 to the contractor and taking $15 as an administration fee and commission. \n\nA retainer is a fee that is paid in advance to secure the services of a staffing agency. Primarily retainers are only requested by high-end executive search firms who conduct long, complicated searches for talents such as surgeons, lawyers, professors, and CFOs. In this instance, the hiring company would pay a large sum upfront to the agency, and then the remainder of their fee once the ideal candidate accepts a job offer. \n\nChances are, Company ABC will be paid by perm or temp placement fees only. Speak to the interviewer briefly about fee structures, showing that you come from a place of full understanding.", "\"I fully understand how recruitment and staffing agencies make a profit. My educated guess is that you earn a profit through permanent placement fees and temp fees. Could you share with me what your fee percentage is? My current agency charges 20-22% depending on the difficulty of the position and the location of our search.\"", "\"From my research, I understand that Company ABC makes a profit from placement fees. I am familiar with three fee styles; the permanent search fee, which is a flat rate. The other is a temp fee, added onto a contractors' hourly wage. The other is a retainer where the client pays a large percentage upfront, similar to hiring an attorney. Which fee structure is used most at Company ABC?"]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "Name for me some reasons why a job seeker would want to work as a temp.", "answers": ["Although it may seem strange to some people, there are many reasons why a job seeker would want to work as a temporary employee. Job seekers from the beginning of their career, into retirement age, can all enjoy the perks of temp work. Some of these benefits include: \n\n- Flexibility. As a temp worker, you can agree to take or turn down work at your leisure. For retired folks who travel a lot, temp work is excellent for seasonal needs.\n- Buying time. Temp workers can earn money as contractors until they find the right permanent opportunity. \n- Comply with work restrictions. Temp opportunities are often a better fit for people waiting on permanent residency or citizenship who may have federal work restrictions. \n- Fill resume gaps. Temp offers job seekers the opportunity to learn new skills in a variety of settings, expanding their resume.\n- Fast-track to employers. Temps are often offered a permanent position after their assignment is complete if the hiring authorities are impressed with their performance. \n\nDiscuss with the interviewer why you believe some candidates would prefer to take on temporary assignments.", "\"I have met many people who highly prefer working temp, for a variety of reasons. The most common reason being wanting to build out their resume to include more skills, and avoid resume gaps while they search for the perfect permanent opportunity. I have also met many semi-retired folks who temp as food samplers on weekends to supplement their retirement income. Temp is an excellent solution for many people.\"", "\"I have worked as a temp in the past. My reasoning was to earn money during the summer between university. I found this solution very beneficial as it rounded out my resume and helped me to network as well. Other people may like to temp if they want the flexibility, or if they have work restrictions due to personal circumstance.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "What advice would you give to a recent grad with no work experience?", "answers": ["Company ABC is all about empowering their candidates, which includes giving sound career and job-search advice to the candidates with whom they work. Talk to the hiring authority about the help that you would give to a recent graduate, with no work experience, who needed to round out their resume. Your advice could be to volunteer more, add in some temporary work, take additional coursework, and more.", "\"I am a strong believer in the power of volunteer work. Statistics show that 3 out of 4 hiring managers prefer to hire candidates with recent volunteer experience. For that reason, I advise new grads that their volunteer work should be on their resume, and it can trump work experience if highlighted to an employer correctly.\"", "\"The best piece of advice that I could give a recent grad is to continually educate themselves in the form of online coursework, reading the right books, and taking advantage of personal development opportunities. I would also recommend they network and get out in their community. Many jobs come through networking, so it's important to get your name out there.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "In which categories does Company ABC recruit?", "answers": ["The hiring authority at Company ABC needs to be sure that you have done your homework on their organization before attending your interview. There are a plethora of areas where recruitment work is prevalent. \n\nTo find out the categories where Company ABC recruits begin by looking at the job postings they have advertised on their website. Also, you can read some of the copy on their website, or look for customer reviews. List 3-5 industries from your research.", "\"When I looked through the job openings on your website, the most popular categories were Industrial & Manufacturing, Retail & Sales, and Office, Clerical & Administrative. In total, I believe you had around 400 jobs available just in those three categories. I was thrilled to see the high volume of open jobs. This volume tells me that your business development professionals and recruiters are hard at work!\"", "\"From my research, the most popular categories for Company ABC appear to be IT, Hospitality & Administrative. Is this accurate? I saw the greatest volume of positions available in these three categories on your website. Also, many of your client reviews come from clients in these industries.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "Of the areas where Company ABC recruits, which are you most knowledgeable?", "answers": ["It's impossible to be an expert in every job category. However, if you have worked as a generalist in the recruitment industry, you do know that it's possible to have a few favorites where your performance shines! \n\nOf all the job categories that Company ABC recruits for, which areas do you believe you are the most knowledgable? Discuss these and why you are most comfortable in these categories.", "\"For many years, I worked as a temp recruiter focusing solely on industrial and warehousing. For this reason, I would say that I am most knowledgable in these areas. I can readily help your clients in the transportation and logistics industries as well. I have a firm grasp on  industry jargon as well as the certifications and regulations that come with such safety-based industries.\"", "\"I see that Company ABC recruits in a variety of areas. Of these categories, sales and retail are the topics that I know best. I have worked in retail and sales, and have a strong idea of the type of candidates that are best in commissioned sales jobs. With that said, I am eager to get to know other industries such as hospitality and administration.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "When have you had to change a search due to new information from your client?", "answers": ["Recruitment projects can change on a dime for a variety of reasons. In the staffing industry, you may find that your client calls off a search entirely after you have poured all of your energy into it for two weeks. \n\nOther situations may change, such as their ideal background or candidate education. Perhaps the client forgot to mention that the role requires extensive travel or eventual relocation. \n\nTalk to the interviewer about a time when you had to pivot your search due to new information. Discuss how you reacted and what you did to keep the momentum going. Most of all, Company ABC wants to see that you are adaptable.", "\"Just last month I had a client who needed to find ten territory sales reps in 60 days. The job order was one of the largest that I had ever taken. The territories had been outlined clearly, which was great. I could call candidates and be very clear with them on the travel expectations and percentage of overnight travel. Partway through my search, the client came back and said that decided to hire just five people and double up on the territories. I had to call my shortlisted candidates again and ask them if they were open to much more extensive travel than originally discussed. Luckily, most of them were open to the idea; however, I did lose three top candidates due to the change. One thing that I have learned in the recruitment industry is to be flexible and roll with the punches because situations like this come up all the time.\"", "\"I had a client, after interviewing my top three candidates, decide that they only wanted to see candidates with post-secondary degrees. I moved on to seek out and present only candidates with college degrees. The client was happy in the end and ended up choosing the very first candidate I submitted. I am glad that I complied rather than fight the situation because it all worked out well in the end.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "Tell me about a time you lost a job order or placement to a competitor. How did you react?", "answers": ["Very often, you will work on job orders that are not exclusive. This non-exclusivity means that your client may give the same job order to five different staffing agencies, and may the best recruiter win! This situation is especially challenging when you live in a smaller city, or if the position requires a particular skill set. \n\nCompany ABC needs to see that you are up for the challenge and that you act gracefully and professionally on the days that you don't win. Discuss a situation from the past, highlighting how you reacted and how you made the best of the situation.", "\"I have one particular client who refuses ever to give exclusivity. Most of the time, their open jobs are shopped out to three other staffing agencies. The most recent order was to find a chemical engineer with 15+ years' experience who came from a direct competitor of my client. This search was incredibly specific, and a competing agency had already approached many of the candidates I called. I felt behind the 8-ball most of the search and unfortunately, did not make the final placement. I took the situation for what it was; you win some, and you lose some. I will continue to give priority to this client and offer the best service possible. Also, I will never stop asking for exclusivity - in hopes that they change their mind one day.\"", "\"I made an in-person client call to discuss a few sales openings with a prevalent advertising company in our region. I was eager to win their business and had a lot of great questions prepared for our meeting. Although I felt the meeting went well, the client called me the next day to tell me they gave the business to our competitor because their fees were lower. Our agency keeps integrity in our pricing, so I was unable to negotiate enough to win the business. I took the situation gracefully because I know that what our agency offers is much more full-service that the competitor they chose. I ended up hearing back from the client a short time later expressing that they wanted to give our agency a try after all. It never pays to burn a bridge, and I am so happy that I stuck to my process and remained professional throughout our initial interactions.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "What are some professional goals you have set for yourself this year?", "answers": ["Company ABC knows that only the most eager recruiters win job orders and make placements since the staffing industry is competitive and challenging. Show the interviewer that you have professional goals and that you are keen to make a name for yourself in the staffing industry. \n\nProfessional goals can include earning a promotion, attending an industry-conference to expand your network, or taking additional courses to broaden your recruitment knowledge.", "\"This year I plan to attend the Staffing World conference in Las Vegas to infuse some new contacts into my network. I have been in the recruitment industry for eight years, and it's easy to become complacent with a steady pipeline of business. This year it's important to me that I gain new contacts while also learning more about the way technology is changing our industry.\"", "\"I am new to my career, so it's important to me that I carve out my professional path from the start. This year I have decided to seek out a mentor in the recruitment industry who can help me to reach my goals while keeping my knowledge current, and continually expanding my understanding of the staffing industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "Are you willing to work outside of the regular 9-5?", "answers": ["In staffing, you may be asked to work outside of a typical Monday to Friday work week, depending on your clients and candidate needs. If you have a candidate who cannot interview during standard work hours, you may need to conduct a phone interview at 7 PM to accommodate their needs. If you do temp staffing, you may have warehouse clients who call you at 6 AM to report a worker who did not show up for their early-morning shift. \n\nMany recruiters have their cell phones on 24/7 and check their email on weekends. Show Company ABC that you are willing to accommodate the varying needs of your clients and candidates.", "\"In the world of staffing, I do not expect to work a strict 40 hour per week schedule, but I also know that I'm looking for a work-life balance. As needed, I will be available to my clients and candidates. I have email on my phone and am sure to be on top of my candidates' start dates, promptly checking in with my clients even on weekends and evenings.\"", "\"In staffing, I anticipate working over 40 hours per week, especially around final deadlines. That said, that comes with some limits as I do value my work-life balance. Could you share with me the expectations for this role?\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "What type of office set up helps you to be the most productive?", "answers": ["Some recruitment firms offer individual offices, some a work-from-home environment and others, a bullpen style set up. As a recruiter, you may hear the word 'bullpen' often. This word is slang for a workspace area filled with desks and no separating walls. Everyone works together in an open space. Think 'Wolf of Wallstreet.' \n\nTalk to the interviewer about the type of work environment you prefer, being sure not to single yourself out by speaking negatively of one particular work style over another. Overall, the interviewer will be looking for your ability to concentrate and work well despite your outside surroundings.", "\"I am self-led and driven, which makes me capable of working productively in nearly any work environment. When I started my first job in staffing, I worked in a bullpen environment. Now, I have a private office; however, our agency is busy, and there is always a lot of buzz around me. I look for a collaborative team more than I look for features like a private office.\"", "\"Being newer to my career in staffing, I see a lot of value working in an open environment where there is a lot of collaboration on projects. I am eager to learn from your talented recruiters. Could you share with me the office set up at Company ABC?\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "Are you a patient individual? Rate your patience level from 1-10.", "answers": ["Being a recruiter or any professional in the staffing industry requires an immense level of patience. You make a lot of calls every day, wait for candidates to respond, and wait on contracts to be signed. Often, you will be in a significant rush to make a placement before a competing agency beats you to the punch. You will speak to hundreds of candidates every month, all with their personality quirks and potentially low levels of commitment and communication. The interviewer wants to know that, despite all of these challenges, you can remain confident, professional, and patient. Rate your level of patience from 1-10 and be prepared to give an example that backs your rating.", "\"I rank my patience level an 8 out of 10. There will always be candidates, clients, and situations that test your patience, and I do have room to improve. Recently I had a candidate back out of their accepted job offer on the morning of their start date. Rather than lose my patience, I quickly found a temp for my client, and then continued to search for a new permanent candidate. Of course, I will not work with that candidate again, but that is simply professional boundaries. I would never disrespect someone, or myself, for a situation like that.\"", "\"For the past year, I have worked as a temp recruiter, primarily searching for laborers in the warehousing and logistics sector. As you know, the rate of candidates who no-show or do not perform well is very high in these categories. Rather than lose my patience, I keep focused on the needs of my clients. For this reason, I rank my patience level as a 9 out of 10.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "Recruitment often requires out-of-the-box thinking. Are you creative by nature?", "answers": ["Being creative doesn't necessarily mean that you can paint like Picasso or write songs like Lady Gaga. What creativity means is being able to view, and solve, common issues in a unique way. Creativity can include being willing to take a risk and change your perspective on a topic. \n\nAs a recruiter, being creative is an essential skill since you will often need to look at your clients' needs and pain points in a completely new way. Assure the interviewer that you are creative, giving a work-related example.", "\"I am most certainly a creative individual. One example of my creativity in action would be the prospecting sales script series that I created for our new business development associates. The scripts needed a facelift, so I took my copywriting skills, my sales savvy, and married them into a very effective sales series. Since this implementation, our close rate has increased by 15%.\"", "\"Unconventional thinking in business requires a great deal of creativity. When it comes to placing candidates with non-exclusive job orders, I need to think differently than other competing agencies with the same client job order. I reverse engineer the path of my ideal candidate and, by doing so, I am the first to reach top candidates before many of my competing recruiters.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "Would you take a job order from a client who was acting unethically?", "answers": ["Responsible staffing agencies like Company ABC need to protect their reputation, which includes prescreening clients in various ways. A smart recruiter will look for a history of unexplained employee turnover, previous sexual harassment accusations, stories of discrimination, poor health and safety records, and consistently lousy employee reviews. When meeting with a client for the first time, and they brag about burning through multiple staffing agencies, this is a definite warning sign. Show the interviewer that you will never put the reputation of Company ABC on the line to land a job order.", "\"In the past, I have worked for agencies that will take work from anyone and everyone. I desire to join an agency like Company ABC with a reputation for legit clients and great job opportunities. From my research and the topics we have discussedtoday, it seems that our core values align nicely.\"", "\"I have been trained to be selective on the clients I take on, and I would like to continue with this practice. I have an intake questionnaire that I go through with clients, so everyone goes through the same prescreening process. Then, I conduct an in-person meeting whenever possible so that I can physically see the environment in which my successful candidate would be working.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "How do you continue to educate yourself, as an expert in staffing?", "answers": ["Continued education is critical in the staffing industry as regulations, and technology change all of the time. Company ABC seeks to hire people who are committed to growth within their profession. Some staffing agencies may even pay for continued education opportunities, so feel free to ask the interviewer if this is an option at Company ABC. Talk to the interviewer about how you plan to educate yourself within staffing.", "\"I read a lot and also subscribe to a variety of accounts and LinkedIn groups related to recruitment and staffing. I like to attend at least one conference every year. Last year, I attended a conference where the topics included legal issues in staffing and unconscious bias. Do you offer continued education opportunities to your team members here at Company ABC?\"", "\"Continued education opportunities are important to me, as I grow my knowledge in the recruitment industry. To keep myself up to date, I subscribe to many blogs including that of Company ABC. I am also taking a couple of certification courses on ethical staffing and conscious recruitment. Could you share with me the education opportunities present at Company ABC?\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "Why should Company ABC hire you over our other candidates?", "answers": ["This question can be incredibly tough for job seekers to answer. This query requires you to brag about yourself on the fly while choosing compelling items from your career highlight reel. \n\nThink to the job posting or job description, and the core values of Company ABC. How do your soft and hard skills match what the company is looking for, in a team member? \n\nThis question should not be used to give a generic answer like you have 'strong attention to detail.'  Focus on factors that are unique to you. Rely on your past achievements and accolades!", "\"I believe you should hire me because of my proven ability to resuscitate dormant clients. I am keen on business development activities and will find new accounts for Company ABC within the first couple of weeks of employment. I am well-versed in supporting junior recruiters, and will help them to uncover new and lucrative opportunities as well.\"", "\"Other candidates may have more staffing experience; however, my background in highly competitive sports, as well as door-to-door alarm sales, makes me an excellent candidate for this sales role with Company ABC. I know exactly how my efforts impact my team, and I am very goal-focused while being self-led.\""]}, {"topic": "Staffing+Agencies", "question": "How much money do you want to earn in this role? What does your ideal pay structure look like?", "answers": ["Staffing and recruitment agencies all compensate a bit differently, generally leaning to what works best for their recruiters based on the type of recruitment they are performing. \n\nSome of these pay structures include 100% commission, draws against commissions, full salary, a salary-commission blend, and monthly guarantees. Be upfront with the interviewer about your compensation expectations. The clearer you are, the higher the chance that you will get what you need.", "\"I currently earn a base salary of $65,000 plus commission for overall earnings in the $105-110K range annually. My current position offers a higher base salary; however, the overall commission structure is not as generous as what you offer at Company ABC. Overall, I would like to see a compensation package that includes health benefits, a minimum of 4 weeks' vacation time, and earning potential in the $125K+ range for my first year.\"", "\"I understand that first-year recruiters earn in the $40-50K range, often with a blend of an hourly wage plus commission on placements. I am happy with an offering in this range, as this gives me room to learn and grow. Could you share with me more specifics on the overall compensation plan at Company ABC?\""]}]